MY LIBERATION NOTES
Damn it. It's not just us
who's been taking money on the side.
He's raked in even more dough than us.
He must want to get rid of us
and keep it all to himself.
Chairman Shin must know that. So why?
Why do you think he's doing nothing?
Have it your way.
Yes, sir.
I'm sure he's waiting.
He's waiting for us to take down Baek.
Listen, Ja-gyeong.
Let's get him.
Come on, we can take him down together.
Listen.
I'm…
completely exhausted.
SUPERMARKET
It's just what you say when you want
to end it with a woman, isn't it?
"The woman I used to live with died."
"Because of me."
No! Go away!
You damn mutts!
Go! Go away! Go! I said, go!
Hey!
Hey! Get lost! Go!
Goddamn mutts.
I told you, they're wild dogs.
You keep making things worse.
Today, I'll get my arm bit off,
and tomorrow, a broken nose.
Misfortunes should come in small doses,
but you keep stopping them
and making them bigger.
I'm scared every time you stop them.
"Now it's gotten even bigger."
"How bad is it going to be?"
You…
have to kill your instincts.
You have to go to the city and numb them.
So that instead of talking
about frogs being crushed to death,
you have to be able
to sincerely talk about superficial stuff
like other women do.
Until you get sick of it.
Until you're sick to death of men.
Women with sharp instincts can be scary.
You…
scare me.
As long as you live in a place like this…
you won't be able to kill your instincts.
Gosh, I see you've had a lot to drink.
I should take a picture of us
being so chummy.
Gu.
Now we can say
we've watched the stars together.
Get up.
SANPO SINKS
ALPHA RETAIL
Is this Sanpo City Hall?
Good afternoon.
I live at 748-6, Gondal-dong.
There are dangerous dogs
on the way to Gondal Reservoir.
The new product orientation
will begin now!
Yes, on the way to Gondal Reservoir.
Yes, all right.
-Yes, thank you.
-Sir.
Yes, let's go.
Since we have new employees,
why don't we move around
the assistant managers?
I think Jeong A-reum and Yeom Chang-hee
on my team should be separated.
Why?
Are they on bad terms?
Well, Yeom is
in charge of A-reum's father's store,
and both of them failed to get promoted
for the second time.
I'm afraid things will only get worse.
But who'd take A-reum? I'd take Yeom.
Yes, I'd take Yeom too.
Let me introduce our main product
for the second half.
As you know, retro is trending right now.
So we've given our liquor a retro style.
It's a collaboration with Jingwang Liquor.
It's 16.9 percent alcohol
and goes down nicely
with a refreshing taste.
Sujak, a masterpiece in the world of soju.
From the first scent to the aftertaste.
SUJAK
What?
You can all take a bottle with you.
Excuse me.
Can I take two?
Why can't you catch them?
Those dogs run off to the mountains
when they see us.
They recognize the ambulance and our car.
They're in the middle of the field
so they can run away easily.
Well, can't you use the tranquilizer gun?
We have to get close to them for that.
We can't shoot at them from that far.
But what's the point of setting the traps?
They won't go in.
They won't even go near them.
They're in the field during the day.
But at night, they roam
around the village looking for food.
When I see those glowing eyes in the dark…
Gosh. They look like wolves, you know.
My kids might run into them at night.
That's what I'm most afraid of.
Well, we'll wait for a week. If the traps
don't work, we'll call a specialist.
Please check the traps periodically.
I'm telling you, they won't.
Thanks anyway.
-Sure, have a good day.
-Goodbye.
SANPO SINKS
Damn it. He saw me.
Just stop by for a second.
I have something to give you.
At what time?
-Hey.
-Yes?
-Go sit next to A-reum.
-Yes, sir.
What do I do?
What? Is this your seat?
No, it's fine.
All right, everyone. Fill your glasses.
Here.
Cheers.
-Cheers!
It looks great.
Who wraps it in dried laver these days?
How tacky.
Put it away.
Just eat it the way you want.
Clearly, you haven't had
high-quality tuna before.
This isn't exactly high-quality either.
Go on and eat.
What's the best way to enjoy it then?
Look at the meat. It's fatty.
This type of meat
tastes best
with just a little bit of wasabi.
Just a little bit of wasabi.
I said I'd treat you to a nice meal,
but you want cold noodles?
Let's eat something else.
I have enough money.
That's what I want to eat.
We'll have some sushi too then.
Why do you keep glancing at me?
Do you think he beat me?
Here, look. It's just fashion.
I had a big fight with that jerk
at his place before.
That asshole is so cheap.
He was all furious, but I could see
that he was throwing only the cheap stuff.
Things like mug cups
that cost 1,000 or 2,000 won.
Then he comes
and trashes my place like that.
He completely ruined my wallpaper.
The most expensive thing
in my house is the wallpaper.
If it gets dirty, I have to pay
500,000 won when I move out.
It's 500,000 won.
Hey jerk, you better wire me the money.
You'd better. Before I sue you.
So how would you score this guy?
About 15 points?
He wasn't bad.
But I think 15 is too generous.
He's violent and he cheated on you.
Well…
He didn't make excuses.
When he cheated and got caught,
he panicked for a second
and apologized right away.
It's like he becomes stupid
when he gets caught doing something bad.
Like a puppy that made a mess.
There are a lot of crazy jerks
who do bad things
and blame you for it.
So, Mi-jeong,
What's your boyfriend's score?
I guess he's at least above 15
since he doesn't make excuses either.
And?
And? What else?
You'll be surprised if you see him.
You might think he's homeless.
He must be one hell of a guy.
Am I scary?
He says I scare him.
I guess you see right through him.
Just tell him to grovel.
You should grovel when you're scared.
But they always want to run away.
He does have some problems.
Since when did we care about that?
Even with the same person,
you can name a thousand reasons
to love them,
and a thousand reasons not to.
Look at Chang-hee.
He hates Jeong A-reum so much,
even for wearing circle lenses.
I wear them too, you know.
Wearing circle lenses could be
one of the thousand reasons to love me
and one of the thousand reasons
to hate Jeong A-reum.
There's no reason.
You just love
or hate someone because you want to.
Hey.
Here, it's alcohol.
It's really good.
I want to give it to Gu,
but I'm going to be late tonight.
Make sure to tell him it's from me!
My sister is on her way home.
I'll have to take the train.
Why don't you go home
with your brother then?
I don't take a cab
with that brat alone. It's gross.
Why do you always call it the train,
Ms. Yeom?
Like an old person.
What else should I call it then?
Doesn't everyone call it the subway?
It doesn't run underground in Gyeonggi.
Why would they dig up the ground?
The land is mostly empty.
Don't make it so obvious
you live in Gyeonggi.
Just call it the subway.
I do live in Gyeonggi.
Hello?
What are you up to? Are you off work?
Yes.
Are you on your way home?
No, I'm having a drink with my colleagues.
Where?
It's close by.
Want some octopus? You like octopus.
She's the one who wants it. She's just
trying to use someone else as an excuse.
Don't you?
Just tell them you're leaving
and join us here. It's fresh.
Tae-hun owes you a meal anyway, right?
Come on. My sister
cooks octopus very well.
Come and let's enjoy
its sweetness together.
Start cooking. Gi-jeong says she'll come.
And he'll pay.
I was going to take her
to a nice place, not here.
Octopus is more than
what she deserves for what she did.
She just picked up a record for you.
This is his treat.
I'm just trying to get your sales up.
What's the matter?
I've just been invited over for a meal.
By that guy?
No.
By my friend, his sister.
She called and said he'd buy me
the meal he said he would tonight.
I'm not sure if I should go or not.
Hello?
Gyeong-seon called you without asking me
because she wants to eat octopus.
So don't worry about it.
Should I not come then?
I just thought it was rude
to invite you so abruptly.
I wanted to take you to a nice place.
I mean, it's my place, so…
You mean, your home upstairs?
No.
My sister's bar.
Well, I don't mind.
I have to go. Bye.
It's close to here, right?
Yes. It's behind the food alley,
three minutes away.
Oh, Gosh. Three minutes.
It's so close. I'm nervous.
Don't rush. Take your time.
I'm about to cross another mountain now.
My first encounter with the guy
who rejected me.
You can do this.
I can do this.
I don't like that lady.
Why not? She's my friend.
Is that why you don't like her?
Welcome.
Hello.
You're here.
Sit, you came on a good day since there
are no customers. Let's have a drink.
Sure.
Please have a seat.
Okay.
Where's Gyeong-seon?
She'll be down soon.
I see.
Did you have dinner?
Yes.
What would you like to drink?
Beer.
And a bottle of soju, please.
-You want to mix them?
-Yes.
Sure.
I wanted to take you to a nice place.
This place is nice too.
I also like octopus.
All right.
Should I mix them for you?
-Sure.
-Right.
I get tipsy really quickly, you know.
So when I drink soju bombs,
I get all hyped up in ten minutes.
I really was going
to take you to a nice place.
This place is nice, really.
Bottoms up?
Okay.
In exactly ten minutes,
I'll be all hyped up and chatty.
Ten minutes?
Well, that is fast.
Thank you.
I mean it.
I tried to cross a mountain.
Thanks to you, I was able to cross it.
I mean, there was
this mountain in front of me.
And crossing it
has given me courage.
Now I want to face
the mountains one by one
instead of avoiding them.
So today…
I came here
to get over the embarrassment--
Why are you embarrassed?
I'm treating you
to thank you for the favor.
Thank you
for coming.
All right. I've had two soju bombs.
I'll become really energized now.
It's from my brother.
It's not some excuse I made up.
He really asked me.
I know.
He texted me.
Don't you have anything to say?
That's a surprise.
You just sounded
like one of those dull women.
What?
Do you want me to apologize?
If you have something to say, say it.
Women always ask for things
like I owe them something.
I don't owe you anything, do I?
That's how life is.
It seems to go well
and then stabs you in the back.
Did you think
it was always going to be peachy?
Idiot.
It's not like I asked for a diamond.
It'd be easier to get you a diamond.
How do you worship someone?
I have no idea.
You were ready to let a dog
bite off your arm.
And yet, you find it hard to hold a woman?
You think it's cool to endure pain
with clenched teeth,
and it's dull to have a cute, happy life
with a woman?
Which is harder?
Getting your arm bitten off by a dog
and getting your nose broken,
or being nice to the woman you like?
Which do you think is harder?
You treated me like a fool
who couldn't even get her money back.
You're no better.
You went to Sanpo Middle School?
Yes, I finished middle school in Sanpo.
Do you know Yeom Chang-hee, by any chance?
He's my younger brother.
He went to Sanpo Middle School too.
-Really?
-Yes.
You're his senior.
He actually works near here as well.
He's probably drinking
somewhere around here.
-You should ask him to come.
-No. God, no.
I'd never. I'm sick of him.
Hello.
What took you so long?
Hey, the octopus tastes great.
Come have a seat.
-You were dying to eat it.
-Yes.
What?
What happened to your hand?
This?
I got hurt.
Hey, divorced dad. Unless you want
to be shot dead, go get me some beer.
Watch what you say.
Watch what you say,
or my sister will kick your ass.
What's with you?
She's my guest.
It was…
Yu-rim's birthday that day.
We didn't know each other then.
Yu-rim and I were just having dinner,
and we happened to overhear her.
She apologized many times afterward.
She wanted to apologize to Yu-rim too,
but I told her not to.
Oh, no! The stove!
I really left the stove on.
Hui-seon, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
You don't have to apologize anymore.
Right. She didn't know any better then.
It's okay. Let's just drink.
Hui-seon and I are
going to take care of Yu-rim for
the rest of our lives and then die.
Her mom made another family
with another man and had…
Had another child.
We'll never let her feel betrayed
and hurt like that ever again.
We're not going to give our affection
to anyone else until the day we die.
We're going to die after loving
and cherishing just Yu-rim alone.
That is
the only reason why I'm still alive.
But he won't die single like us.
He's seeing a woman.
I told you, I'm not.
I don't have anyone.
I don't.
I really don't.
What was that? Why are you
so concerned about what she thinks?
What's going on?
Do you have feelings for Gi-jeong?
I…
told him I liked him,
and he rejected me.
Yu-rim.
We won!
A very nice play from Cho Tae-hun!
For God's sake.
-We need to talk.
-No way, you prick.
Hey!
No thanks, brother.
Where's Chang-hee?
He went to the district office.
He'll be here soon.
A-reum's father apparently
keeps giving him errands.
He should take care of
his own business with the district office.
Does he think
the HQ employees are his butlers?
Just between you and me.
I'm trying to separate
A-reum and Chang-hee,
but no one wants to take A-reum.
So I'm thinking,
how about you and Chang-hee switch teams?
You want me
to sit next to A-reum?
Yes.
Gosh.
What?
It could be different with you.
Why don't we
wait and see for a while?
Chang-hee seems okay these days.
He didn't even complain about going
to the district office. He was smiling.
I mean, he used to throw
a tantrum over things like that.
But today, he just smiled and said,
"I'll see you later."
He does seem different, doesn't he?
Is he dating someone?
I don't think so.
-Here.
-Hey.
Man, it's hot.
I'm sorry I kept you waiting.
No, I just got here.
Look at you.
-I'm okay.
-What do you want to eat?
I'll just have the ox bone soup.
You?
Same.
-Excuse me. Three ox bone soup, please.
-Where's the cup?
What is it?
It can't be a girl.
You're not going to tell me?
A few days ago,
I almost died trying to hold in my poop.
It was right about to come out so I had
to barge into my neighbor's house.
The guy who works for your dad?
-Yes.
-The one that jumped that long distance?
Yes! It was so freaking cool.
I didn't even have time
to turn the lights on,
but the power was out anyway.
So I was sitting in the dark,
and I saw something glimmering
next to my butt.
It was a bidet.
I thought, "This guy uses a bidet."
"Of course. I'm sure he used to be rich."
He seemed like a guy who used to be rich.
I just had the feeling.
Then I saw something else in front of me.
I was like, "Is it a glowing watch?"
No, it was a key to a Royce, my dream car.
The moment I saw it,
I could picture his past at once.
A man who fell from the very top.
A man who doesn't care where
he puts the key to his luxury car.
My savior.
I don't know why, but I wanted
to get close to him. I just did.
It's like my soul knew.
"Cling to him. Grovel, Chang-hee."
And I really groveled.
Well, you know I'm good at it.
But to him, I just shut up and groveled.
I don't know his age,
but I treat him like he's older.
How great are my animal instincts?
He likes me too, you know.
If I go…
"Hey."
"Your car that you just ditched somewhere.
Can I drive it?"
He'll let me.
I'm 100 percent sure.
What if he only has the key?
You want to ruin it, right?
Okay, I get it.
Since that day, what A-reum says
doesn't bother me anymore.
She's just too trivial
to ruin my saintly mood.
I've tried everything to not hate her.
Meditation, Buddhist chants…
None of them worked.
I thought, "When you hate someone,
you just can't help it."
But what I needed was
something beyond mere willpower.
I use his bathroom every morning and night
to check on the key.
Thanks for letting me use your bathroom.
What?
It's good, isn't it?
Good night, then.
I hope he and Mi-jeong make up soon
so I can bring it up.
Mi-jeong, I'm counting on you.
Throw yourself at him!
SOMETHING GOOD WILL HAPPEN TO YOU TODAY
I told you,
I don't care if you're
a notorious criminal or even an alien.
So what's the big deal?
I still think you're okay.
So let's carry on.
Let's keep going.
VILLAGE BUS STOP
SANPO
It's now chilly…
in the morning.
I don't get why you'd ask a man
for dating advice.
Shouldn't you ask another woman
for that sort of thing?
To me, it looks like an excuse
to make a move on him.
Am I overreacting here?
No, you're not.
I'm sorry.
You're absolutely right.
I don't know what to say.
I'm so embarrassed.
Please try to understand
how it makes me feel.
Because you and Mr. Park seem so close,
people are starting to wonder
if he and I have broken up.
I'm really sorry.
I'll be careful.
Gosh, what's wrong with me?
Why are you crying?
Now you're making me feel bad.
No, I…
I'm just so ashamed of myself.
I just embarrass myself every day.
But you have nothing
to worry about though.
I'm not Mr. Park's type.
He didn't even give me
any lottery tickets.
That's right.
What did Ms. Yeom say?
She said she just became close
with Mr. Park
while asking for dating advice.
Did you two have sweet dreams?
Maybe she just made up the whole story.
-Really?
-Yes.
You two seem to
be very interested in your looks.
Nirvana reminds me of you now.
I'd like to buy you two meals
as an apology
without Gyeong-seon.
Please, let me.
Hey.
Hey!
Hello, sir. It's been a long time.
"Export investments
in the second-quarter slump."
"The economy is in a recession
for the fifth straight month."
"This is the longest recession
since the government started giving
monthly economic reports in March, 2005."
"The recession in the real economy is
continuing due to the difficulties
in foreign trade,
but the government believes that it is
not a sign of economic stagnation."
What are you doing?
My partner is a man of few words.
He says nothing all day.
So I've become a slow talker.
I even stutter now.
It's been a while,
so I didn't want to stutter and look bad.
I wasn't able to sleep for days.
I was too angry.
I thought about what made me so angry.
What are you doing here? Are you putting
on a show? Acting like you're broken?
You think I'd put on a show?
Why do I have to act like I'm broken?
Tell me.
I'm taking a break.
For 15 years, I listened
to the drunks yapping
and singing in basements like this.
Then I went home to…
I was practically a dead man walking.
I was barely alive.
But you saved my life
by stabbing me in the back.
Thanks.
You asshole.
You're talking down to me now?
Then what? You stabbed me in the back.
I'm a little busy these days,
making sinks and stuff.
I'll come back if I decide to.
Do I decide that I like making sinks
and want to leave this world behind,
or do I decide that this is the world
that I need to conquer?
It's one or the other.
I'll be back after
I make the decision, so just wait.
If you keep lurking around
and pissing me off,
I will come back for good,
so just wait quietly.
Got it?
Hey, you need a new sink.
Sam-sik!
That son of a bitch. I should just…
Order one from Sanpo Sinks.
I…
I've changed my name.
I'm not the one who texted you
to come to Oido Station that winter.
Mr. Baek had borrowed my cell phone then.
I wouldn't dare to tell you
to come there to drink with me.
I know.
Hyeon-jin told me.
SANPO SINKS
Go ahead, guys.
Let's go before the traffic hits.
Did…
Did that guy go home already?
Your boss who always throws a fit.
Looks like they made up, right?
What do you think you're doing?
Don't follow me.
Go back.
Go away.
You punk. I said, go away.
You little…
I will die if you tell me
that it's just the key you have.
I really want
to live as a saint for a while.
Even if you don't have the car,
please say you do.
Please tell me you'll give it to me
when the time comes.
Please. I want to feel this way
for a little longer.
Listen.
I…
just came back from Seoul.
And you want me to go back?
Gu.
I love you.
Really?
Gu.
Gu!
Gosh, thank you. I love you.
-Ten! Nine! Eight!
-Seven! Six! Five!
-Four! Three! Two! One!
One asshole after another…
Every guy I've ever dated was an asshole.
MY LIBERATION NOTES
Are you nervous?
Call Baek now.
What did Mr. Gu use to do?
I have a feeling
that he'll disappear once I ask that.
My heart has never
settled with one person.
Want a ride?
Oddly enough, I become very gentle.
It's just like then.
You can't always wait for him.
Let's make him anxious.
I'm sorry for calling you out of the blue.
I feel like I'm going to collapse.
Did you miss me?
I don't care
about where I'll go after I die.
Subtitle translation by: Yoon-jung Song
Ripped and synced by
TTEOKBOKKIsubs