MY LIBERATION NOTES
ALL LOCATIONS, CHARACTERS,
ORGANIZATIONS, AND INCIDENTS
DEPICTED IN THIS DRAMA
ARE ENTIRELY FICTITIOUS
Mom…
They say you can't choose to die
peacefully in your sleep
no matter how rich you are.
And Hye-suk managed to do it.
It's because this family
has such good luck.
Mom, Dad, and even the daughter-in-law
all passed away in their sleep.
That's my dream, too, you know?
I feel so bad for my brother.
Je-ho!
-I'm so sorry.
-Mom.
Mom…
My poor brother.
CREMATORIUM
LATE KWAK HYE-SUK
When I end up lying there…
who do you think…
will be standing here?
Probably me.
Let's…
get married.
It seems like an artificial joint.
What do you want to do with it?
How does this work?
Well, if you want us to discard it,
we can.
Pack it up, please.
LATE KWAK HYE-SUK
Get some sleep, Dad.
SANPO SINKS
I'll do some grocery shopping tomorrow.
Just have them delivered.
I did that, too.
It's gone bad.
I'm not having breakfast, don't bother.
I'm off.
Have a fried egg at least!
See you tonight.
Damn it.
SANPO CITY
The bus is here.
It's my treat today.
Why would you treat us? It's fine.
I should since you came all the way
to the funeral.
Mi-jeong, I didn't know you lived
that far away. It took forever.
It's 29 stops. I counted it myself.
How do you commute from there every day?
Where did you put your mom's urn?
At home.
Her urn is at your house?
Is that okay?
Why wouldn't it be?
Isn't it illegal?
No, it isn't.
I see.
I heard it was illegal to scatter them.
Aren't the urns also managed
in some system or something?
What do you think dying is?
It means you're out of the system.
Why not a columbarium?
How could we leave her somewhere else?
So it's okay to keep it at home.
Isn't it scary?
It still doesn't feel real, does it?
I still don't know what's going on.
The ambulance came that day
and said they don't move patients
who are in cardiac arrest.
We asked them desperately
to take her to the hospital,
but they said they couldn't.
Then the police came
to see my mom lying in the bedroom.
They asked weird things like,
"Did you have a fight?"
"How many insurance policies do you have?"
That's a really odd experience.
AUNTIE X
Hello?
Why didn't you pick up?
I've been calling you since before.
I was busy.
I fried some anchovies and shrimp.
Pick them up when you finish work.
Dad doesn't like dry dishes.
Hey, your father's a widower now.
Tell him to eat whatever's offered.
Just come and take them.
This damn…
Welcome.
I'll have 300g of beef for soup
and 2.4kg of pork ribs.
I see. 300g of beef for soup
Actually, make it 3kg.
-3kg of pork ribs, right?
-Yes, please.
Coming right up.
Why didn't you just take a taxi?
We're home.
Damn it.
Hey, Mom definitely died from overwork.
Why do I have to go all the way
to Wangsimni to pick up some food?
She doesn't even know what you like.
She just pretends to care.
I almost threw them out on my way home.
That's enough.
I know she doesn't care about you.
Why does she have to pretend she does?
She must be doing this
to get money from you.
If she even talks about it,
I'll go show her what's what.
-There's nothing stopping me now.
-Seriously…
Don't you know
who put Mom through all that?
Just let Dad eat!
Give me your seal later, Dad.
We'll go and bury it somewhere.
If you let your sister
have her way again, we're done.
I don't even care if we're family.
I won't see you again!
LATE KWAK HYE-SUK
Thank you.
-Thank you, boss.
-Goodbye.
-Thanks.
-Thank you.
I had a great time.
How's Gi-jeong doing?
I mean, she used to come every day.
I kind of miss her.
She goes straight home
after work these days.
Yes, she should.
Her father must be lonely by himself.
He's not alone.
I heard her brother quit his job
and stays at home.
Goodness, it's a pity
she passed away so soon.
You didn't even get to meet her.
I did.
The day she passed away.
In the afternoon.
She bought me lunch.
To think that someone I saw
in the afternoon passed in the evening…
She must have wanted
to meet her son-in-law before she left.
How could you say that in front of her?
So I looked at the envelope,
and it said "Park Jin-u."
So I was like, "What?" And I looked up.
And he said, "Ms. Yeom Gi-jeong
bad-mouthed me a lot, didn't she?"
All the people I've heard so much
about were gathered there,
so I kind of got excited
and put my foot in my mouth.
I was like,
"So this is what a funeral can be like."
I told you, right?
That the girl Gi-jeong said had "nasty"
written all over her face must be pretty.
I picked her out immediately among
all her colleagues. "It's her!"
So I asked Gi-jeong,
"The girl who has 'nasty' written
all over her face. That's her, right?"
And she said,
"Yes."
It came out that she lied, you know?
I was even more shocked
when your mom passed away
than when my mom passed away.
Maybe because
I didn't see it coming at all.
It's natural that you come and you go.
But I wish everyone could leave
at the right time.
When is the right time?
At 80 years old?
You'll feel different when you become 80.
My grandpa used to look
at old people and say
he didn't want to live that long.
He would only live till 80.
But when he turned 80,
I asked, "Grandpa, aren't you supposed
to pass away this year?"
Then he said,
"I don't think so."
Just like that,
he managed to live until he was 90.
And he still said it wasn't time yet.
What if we have a system
where all humans live up to 100?
And die when they turn 100?
Then I'll form a militia when I'm 99.
"Destroy the system!"
I'll run from the system
into the mountains.
There's no such thing as the right time.
But your mother chose a good day.
Friday, Saturday, Sunday.
We got three days off thanks to your mom.
Gi-jeong and her boyfriend, too.
No matter how you look at it,
Gi-jeong's the luckiest one here, right?
Listen.
It would have been shameless
if she was looking for a guy to date
after her mother passed away.
But it's as if she knew
something like this was going to happen.
It was as if she was possessed.
Can you believe her?
Pretending to have lost
her memories after getting rejected.
She was so desperate.
She grabbed onto him in such a hurry.
And then her mom passed away.
So now,
she would be blameless
if she decided to move out.
I can feel it.
Gi-jeong will move out soon.
Seeing that her boyfriend has visited
for three days in a row,
I can tell.
Yes.
Right.
And Chang-hee also quit his job
-at the perfect time, right?
-Yes.
Seriously…
Isn't my sixth sense amazing?
That must have been
why I wanted to quit so badly.
But in retrospect,
I didn't want to quit that badly.
It just felt like the right time to quit.
I guess my soul just knew.
If I weren't unemployed,
who would take care of my dad?
After the three of us go to work,
and without Gu, he'd be all by himself.
The thought makes me tear up.
I was like this when I was younger, too.
When I was in high school,
my homeroom teacher said
we'd be in trouble if anyone skipped
the after-school classes.
I had never skipped them before,
but I really wanted to
go home that day for some reason.
It wasn't like I had anything to do
at home. I just wanted to go home.
So I did.
My grandma was alone at home.
When I said, "I'm home,"
her eyes were open,
but she wouldn't answer me.
Something felt off.
I felt like I had to
hold her hand so I did.
But soon,
I got the chills,
and thought, "She must be gone."
I suddenly got scared,
so I pulled my hand away.
Then I thought, "This isn't right."
So I held her hand tight again.
About five minutes later,
my dad came back.
"Where did you go, leaving Grandma alone?"
It was the first time in my life
telling Dad off like that.
He couldn't say a thing
and just listened to me.
And it kind of felt
cathartic.
If I hadn't skipped school that day,
my grandma would've passed away all alone.
Just like this, my soul knows
and my body just follows.
I never thought…
I would be waiting
for Gi-jeong to come home.
After spending the whole day
with my dad alone,
when Gi-jeong and Mi-jeong come home…
it feels
less lonely.
When you feel lonely,
I hope you remember that Oh Du-hwan
is also feeling lonely somewhere.
And this song is for us.
I didn't say
Or do anything
Just your name alone
Makes my heart ache
Why didn't I know
That you'd be leaving so far away
My love
I guess this is our goodbye
The times I've sulked at you
Without good reason
And the times I've been
Too harsh and negligent
I never got to tell you
How sorry I am
My love
I guess this is our goodbye
No matter how many times I tell myself
That it'd be okay
And that you'd understand
The memories that I cannot forget
-Come a step too late as regret
-It's cold. Let's go.
If only for a day
I could see you again
I would cry for hours on end
In your presence
Even the wind sounds
So quiet in the sky today
My love
I guess this is our goodbye
It still bothers me
that Mr. Gu didn't come.
Don't you have any way of contacting him?
They don't even know his name.
How could she not know
the name of the person she dated?
Good night.
Bye.
No matter how many times I tell myself
That it'd be okay
And that you'd understand
The memories that I cannot forget
Come a step too late as regret
If I get to see you once again
Through all my wishing
-I will thank you before it's too late
-Mom. It's snowing.
My love
I guess
This is our goodbye
LATE KWAK HYE-SUK
Hello, Joy Card Design Department.
Sure, one moment, please.
Hello?
Is this Yeom Mi-jeong?
Yes, this is she.
This is Choi Jun-ho's wife.
It's not me.
He just saved her as my name.
What do you mean?
One moment.
YEOM MI-JEONG (TEMPORARY EMPLOYEE)
I'm saved as "Yeom Mi-jeong"
with "Temporary Employee" in brackets.
Hey.
What are you doing?
Would you like to see who it is?
Damn it.
YEOM MI-JEONG:
I MISS YOU!
LEAVE
Okay.
YEOM MI-JEONG:
WHAT'S GOING ON?
"SOTP" MESSAGING ME
STOP
DELETE OUR CHAT HISTORY
For God's sake.
YEOM MI-JEONG
Is he crazy?
He saved the girl he's having
an affair with as "Mi-jeong"?
Who on earth is the woman?
How would we know?
Does she even work here?
Of course, she does.
No wonder.
People kept whispering about Mi-jeong
at the funeral.
Really?
They said she was dating him
to get a permanent position.
Can't you sue him for that?
Are you busy? Can I stop by?
MR. GU
SEPTEMBER 19
CALL
The number you have called
is not in service.
Please check the number and try again.
My asshole team leader is
having an affair with some employee,
and he saved her number under my name.
No way.
Since everyone knows he hates me,
he must've thought
it'd be safe if he saved it under my name.
I knew he was having an affair.
And with whom.
Who is it?
A while back, I called the two of them
since they were late for a meeting.
And it was eerily identical
how both calls were so silent.
There wasn't any background noise,
as if they were in a vacuum.
For the two of them.
They were in a motel.
It became so obvious after that.
When I saw a shampoo in her bag,
I wondered why she would
carry shampoo around.
It was to avoid smelling the same
by using different shampoos.
When that asshole
would start ranting at me…
Is it that hard?
Font combination, color coordination,
color choice, is that so hard?
-I mean, is it hard?
-She would suddenly
align a stack of papers with a "tap"
in an elegant motion.
-Seriously…
-Then he would
stop ranting at me.
She was signaling him to stop.
Since then, whenever he started ranting,
I'd end up looking at her hands,
wondering when she'd give the signal.
At first, I was grateful
for her fingertips
fluttering like a butterfly.
But now,
when she starts putting papers together,
I want to break all of her fingers.
MS. YEOM, CAN WE TALK FOR A MOMENT?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU THINK YOU KNOW
WE CAN TALK OVER THE PHONE
It's that bastard.
Don't respond.
He must be quaking in his boots.
Just ignore it. Don't even read them.
It's fine. It doesn't take that long
if I take the subway, anyway.
I have to drive you home today.
Besides, my sister
made some dishes for you.
I'll be there in 30 minutes,
so wait at my sister's place.
All right.
Thank you.
Hello.
-You're here.
-Hi.
Hi. Long time no see.
Wait here. The ribs are upstairs.
-Have a seat.
-You didn't have to make ribs.
Tae-hun even paid me to make them for you.
Want some cold beer?
I'll get it myself.
Sure.
I've been a bit busy these days.
You heard, right?
It's been a while since I drank beer.
I know
that it gets harder if I drink.
I know if I drink just a little like this,
it'll be harder on my way home.
I live quite far away, you see.
I know very well it'll be hard.
But I don't want to be strong.
I just want to be knocked out.
I get like this sometimes.
But…
I always feel okay again the next day.
Do grown-ups
get sad, too?
When their moms are gone.
Can't I be your mom?
I want to.
If you don't like it,
just give me the axe, all right?
Let's get married.
Okay, let's.
Bye.
-See you tomorrow.
-I'm off.
-All right.
CHOI JUN-HO
DESIGN TEAM 3
Yeom Mi-jeong.
Just think of it as bad luck.
There's no misunderstanding.
Who on earth would think
you two are having an affair?
Do you know who it is?
The woman he's having an affair with.
Yes.
Who is it?
You can't do this to me.
I took care of you,
and this is how you repay me?
Still…
you shouldn't have
done that at the funeral.
Giggling and playing footsie
under the table!
That's not right.
I don't want
to have friends anymore.
I don't need them.
Why does it feel like that's you?
Something that feels so out of place
and is screaming, "I'm here."
Yeom Mi-jeong.
On Mr. Choi's desktop screen,
I saw messages
from someone set as my name.
The messages were obviously romantic.
I've never done
anything like that with Mr. Choi.
Then why would
Mr. Choi's wife have called me?
My wife says she's never called
the company.
She says she never called here
looking for Yeom Mi-jeong.
How would I know who did what?
It's too bad this kind of incident
occurred before your review
for a permanent position.
On top of that, the assault.
We can't let you guys work
in the same department.
Hello.
Hey.
I still can't believe it.
She came by here that very day.
How could she pass away just like that?
I saw Mi-jeong crying her eyes out
saying she'd lost her dog.
So I asked if she'd found it,
but she said she didn't have a dog,
so I asked, "Well, was it a goat then?"
That's what we talked about.
But that very day…
When was that?
That day, the day she passed.
No, I mean, Mi-jeong…
What about your dad?
Is he holding up alright?
Yes.
You take good care of him.
I will.
Goodbye.
How are Gi-jeong and Mi-jeong doing?
Gi-jeong cries every day,
and Mi-jeong's just the same, I guess.
Mi-jeong is someone
who can't cry
unless she plucks up the courage.
-Thank you, sir!
Sure. Don't forget to send me photos
to let me know you're home later.
-Okay!
All right, off you go.
-Goodbye!
Hey. You're back early.
Did you take the afternoon off?
Yes.
Out of the way!
SANPO SINKS
Where's Dad?
In the field.
Hey, what is this?
What do you mean?
Why did you take out a loan?
HANJO EMERGENCY FUND EASY LOAN
LOAN AMOUNT 2,000,000 WON
I beat someone up a bit.
It's for the settlement.
Who?
Just some crazy bitch.
But why did you need to get a loan?
You don't have two million won?
Show me your bankbook.
-Show me your bankbook now!
-Are you my mom?
You lent money to Chan-hyeok, didn't you?
You stupid brat!
Why the hell did you hit her?
Yeom Je-ho was ripped off
by his little sister.
But what kind of idiot
lends money to her boyfriend?
What's that bastard's number?
Give me that bastard's number!
Are you not going to tell me? Damn it.
He's not in Korea.
Why didn't you tell us?
Do you have no family? No mom, no dad?
I wouldn't have either.
She saw how I was treated after
my trouble with money.
Of course, she wouldn't.
I wouldn't, either.
I'd rather starve to death.
I'd rather be in jail
before letting any of you know.
When did we ever rely on our family?
Gosh, thank you!
Gu…
Where are you now?
How are you doing?
Gu…
My mom died.
Why are you ignoring me
after proposing to me?
You're not even answering my calls.
I've been busy.
Hey.
I'm not dead yet.
I knew it, you two.
Don't worry about it.
Hyeon-a won't say yes, anyway.
What if she does?
He says you won't say yes.
I will.
She said yes.
I need to make dinner.
Did you see the link I sent?
The columbarium.
I did some research,
and that's the best place. And it's clean.
Let's put your mom's urn there.
I want mine to be there, too.
I want to go wherever you put your mom.
You should stay with your mom.
My mom is going to live very long.
And I'm not expecting any visitors.
You'll come see me
if I'm placed next to your mom.
I'll reserve spots
for you and Hyeon-a, too.
So you're going to take us with you?
No, you guys take your time.
Let's stay together, even when we're dead.
So that we won't be bored.
What about Mi-jeong?
What about her?
Is she doing all right?
You should ask her yourself.
Aren't you closer to her than me?
Chang-hee.
I…
need people who are happy.
So, Chang-hee…
you have to be happy.
I carry on thanks to you.
Dad.
Don't worry.
We'll…
be even happier.
But…
for a family of four to be happy…
we need a car.
I think it's my first time
coming to the beach with Dad.
It's the first time we've come
to the beach as a family.
When it was just you and me,
I have memories of going places
with Mom and Dad.
But nothing after Mi-jeong was born.
It's because it was hard for all five
of us to go around on buses and trains.
That's not the reason.
It's because Auntie got into trouble then.
And ever since then, nothing.
The villain of our family is Auntie.
That sounds scary.
I'm going to be an aunt one day.
Hey, it's not possible for us
to become an aunt who robs her family.
Dad loved her, you know?
That's why he cared for her
and sold off his own land.
But this asshole doesn't love us
that much.
You have no idea.
I would give you everything
if I had anything.
I just can't because I don't.
Hey. Once we get married,
let's not bother each other over money.
Yes. Let's not ever do that.
Never mind.
Bother me.
On second thought,
I think I'd give you money, too.
But you need to know this.
We can do that because we love each other.
But do you think our children
will love us that much?
I don't think so, you know?
That's the problem.
Dad loved Aunt, but we didn't.
That's why they say you can get away
with anything if you have love.
You still have
the three of us by your side, Dad.
Dad…
I love you.
I thought I was taking
care of them all this time.
I only realized after she passed away…
that Hye-suk and the kids
were the ones taking care of me.
YEOM MI-JEONG
You're…
doing well, right?
Yes, sir.
YEOM MI-JEONG
I'm not sad at all.
But why do I keep tearing up?
Hello?
It's been a while.
It's Gu.
It has been a while.
How have you been?
Have you managed to liberate yourself?
Of course not.
Have you met someone who worships you?
Let's meet up.
I can't.
Why?
I've gained weight.
I need to lose some weight.
Lose some weight in an hour and meet me.
You haven't gained much.
What?
You've grown your hair.
Aren't I handsome?
And you've cut your hair.
Yes, a little.
You changed your number.
That was a bold move.
I was so angry waiting for you to call.
It's not like you don't know where I live.
I thought you'd be able to
if you really wanted to.
You never called my previous number.
Did you?
I missed you. So much.
It sounds real now that I've said it.
It feels like I really missed you so much.
I wanted to squeeze you
and swallow you down in one mouthful.
Aren't I good at worshiping now?
What is your name?
It's Gu Ja-gyeong.
Subtitle translation by: Yoon-jung Song
MY LIBERATION NOTES
Why didn't you call me sooner?
He'd never let me hit rock bottom.
Do you want a part-time job?
We agreed to get married
when she turns 20.
But when she's 20, I'll be 50. Damn it.
Didn't you say
it was over between you two?
I've always known
what kind of a person you are.
I'll be here for you.
-What?
-You son of a bitch!
When I met you again,
I regretted it.
I do see
a doctor.
Just go.
I'll stay.
Remember this one thing.
Ripped and synced by
TTEOKBOKKIsubs