MY LIBERATION NOTES
ALL LOCATIONS, CHARACTERS,
ORGANIZATIONS, AND INCIDENTS
DEPICTED IN THIS DRAMA
ARE ENTIRELY FICTITIOUS
Wait here.
I'll go.
I'm getting goosebumps.
Why am I getting goosebumps?
Gu, you're not some regular guy, are you?
You used to be a national athlete, right?
I mean, Gu…
Why is someone like you
picking peppers in the countryside?
Go wash up.
Wash up and come eat.
Why are you wearing a hat
when we're eating?
They said I should avoid the sun.
Good going, wasting
your money just to get uglier.
Gosh.
Are there this many track and field
athletes with the last name "Gu?"
Can you just tell me your name?
Gu Jin-seok?
Gu Ja-yoon?
Just wait and see. Your name
must be in here, I'm telling you.
Gu Ja-gyeong!
Will you just eat?
Fine.
Gu Chang-mo?
I can't believe I know Gu Chang-mo.
No, that can't be.
Even if I know, I should pretend I don't.
I don't know anything.
Gu Yoon-hoe?
Gu Bon-gyeong?
You're really perfect
for track and field, Gu.
You know, those who challenge
their limits all on their own usually have
a solitary side, right?
What's your specialty? The 800m?
Just let me rest.
All right.
I have nothing to say, okay?
And nothing I want to hear.
Okay.
Where are you going?
To your house.
Thank you
for thinking of us too. I feel bad.
How was the party?
Good, everyone ate and left.
Your mom will be cleaning up for a while.
We all helped before we left.
I'm sure
there's still a lot of work left to do.
Come on. Be careful.
Why does it have to be here?
It'll be noisy.
How can we drink in the yard?
Your dad's there.
My God!
What's with your face?
It's under construction.
Gi-jeong, come join us!
I can't drink if I want
these bruises to go away!
What did she do to her eyes?
I have no idea.
What about her eyes?
Why didn't you bring a table or something?
Just eat, dumbass.
My back hurts!
He suddenly started running,
and from that moment,
it was awesome. I could just feel it.
"He'll make the jump"
And he did.
Like paper flying through the air.
Anyone can do that if they train.
You think you can?
I can.
Bullshit.
Care to bet? How much?
If you do it within a week, 500,000 won.
A week isn't enough.
Then within a month.
You won't make it, moron.
It was scorching today.
My scalp felt as if it was melting.
"So this is how I kick
the bucket, picking peppers."
"Peppers, me, and the sun…"
My mind was all over the place.
But seeing Gu jump
like that really blew my mind.
It's a skill I would've shown off
right away, but he hid it for a year.
Someone who knows how to hide
how cool he is, is a genuinely cool guy.
I knew Gu was special.
I could tell by his face.
How could you tell that by just his face?
I just can tell.
A face like yours or mine says,
"Yes, I'm nothing special.
What you see is what you get."
You little…
We're much better off.
Those who seem special but are not,
they're way more disappointing.
We're not like that. We're just
a little disappointing at first sight.
Take him for example.
Whenever he sees a girl
he doesn't know at a school reunion,
he goes quiet and acts cool.
But oddly enough, when he does that,
it somehow actually looks cool.
So some girls are attracted to him
and go on a few dates with him.
Then they won't even go near him.
They all just avoid him.
Hey, that's not true.
It is true, dumbass.
That habit's like a disease, man.
When you first meet someone,
you should act like you're nothing special
to keep their expectations low
and show them your good points later on.
Then you should say,
"What? You noticed that?"
"You're right. I can see that's my charm.
I had no idea."
But you're all about bluffing.
Then what am I supposed to do?
Act like you're nothing special!
I really am nothing special!
Nothing about me is special!
Look carefully. There must be something.
Ask a woman to find it for you.
They'll do all the work.
Mi-jeong! Are you on a diet?
Yes!
All right, do your best!
I hope you'll get prettier.
Do we not have a new one?
No, I've been meaning to buy one.
I'll go pick one up.
This late at night?
We'll just get it tomorrow.
Why am I feeling sad?
Why am I sad?
He always holds back.
He takes a step forward but then stops.
I'm just going to
keep wanting until the day I die.
Mi-jeong.
Don't ask for love like me.
I'm a great person.
I won't ask to be loved.
I asked him what he stares at
every day in the yard.
He said mountains.
He said if you piled up 7.7 billion 1-won
coins, it'd be as big as that mountain.
Why 7.7 billion coins?
Don't you get it?
I got what he was saying right away.
It's 7.7 billion.
What about 7.7 billion?
The world's population, moron.
Let's say I'm a 1-won coin. Then
7.7 billion coins are about 5,000 tons.
As heavy as that mountain.
If you convert the whole thing into coins,
everything becomes much clearer.
Me and the world's population.
So?
Jeez.
I'm trying my best to live.
But would you even be able to find me,
just a coin, in that mountain of coins?
Are they sorted by country?
Hey, just forget it. Just stop.
Why wouldn't we be able to find you?
We're not piled up like a mountain.
That's not it, idiot!
Enough about Mr. Gu!
It's just something some alcoholic said.
It must have been
one hell of a long jump. Damn it.
Damn it.
How dull my life must be…
It's not like I saw Yuna Kim jump.
It was just some guy,
but I'm excited all day.
I've never felt real joy,
pleasure, or excitement in my life.
Except during the 2002 World Cup.
And then it was over.
That's why I'm going on
and on about it like this.
As I go on about it this way,
it somehow makes me feel
something similar to joy, you know?
Goodness. Take this.
Here.
You guys may have gotten older,
but it's just like when you used to
play house here as kids.
Your bodies got bigger,
but you're still the kids
who used to put grass on bottle lids
and serve it up saying, "Enjoy."
When the time is right,
you're supposed to meet your life partner,
get married, have kids,
and watch them grow up.
How come so many kids these days
refuse to do that
and just grow old all alone?
Shouldn't something have changed
since back when you used to play house?
My goodness.
You must be sick of it, too, right?
Even I can tell.
Try having a kid.
You'll feel full without eating.
Every day will be amazing.
You'll be invincible.
No one can beat you.
No one can beat parents.
But you don't know anything about that.
Goodness gracious.
Mother.
After you had us,
you enjoyed two or three short years
of joy and delight,
then your life got miserable.
Do you really want to pass
that kind of life onto us?
You little…
And if we want we want
to feel joyful at all times,
should we keep having kids
until we're 80? Until we die?
It's hot. Why do you close the window?
You don't even turn on the AC.
What do I do? It's so delicious.
I was full, but this is so good.
Goodness. All he knows
is how to run his mouth.
You may have gotten bigger and taller,
but it's still you.
Right?
I don't expect anything from you.
I'm just happy when you smile.
And when you cry, I wonder what happened.
Quit pigging out, asshole!
Your stomach's going to pop.
-Are you jealous of this?
-Shut up.
Just his size has changed.
SUPERMARKET
I'm a great person.
I won't ask to be loved.
I bought some soju.
Take this.
How much was it?
It's fine.
Do you even have money?
Enough for that.
Are you sure?
That you and I
will have become
different people when spring comes?
You said I would if I worshipped you.
You've never tried it, right?
In my experience, you change once
you do something you've never done before.
Have you decided to do it?
I already started.
Earlier today.
Don't give me that.
Do you know how sad it makes me?
I know, dumbass.
-Hey.
-I have the most hair around here.
Keep it down! Call it a night already!
Don't you have work tomorrow?
ALPHA RETAIL
I guess she's really upset.
Did I tell you?
That my niece passed
the Grade Seven Public Service Exam?
Yes.
So I took her to the mall
to buy her a set of clothes,
but the sales clerk asked
if we were friends!
She's 27 years old.
I felt so bad for her.
But she's still sore about it.
Take a look. This is me and my niece.
Do we really look like friends?
Yes. You really do.
Really?
Did I tell you already?
Two years ago,
I went to a bar with a hat on,
and they asked me for my ID.
I was with all my friends too.
-Help, please call me.
-I was the only one they asked.
My friends were so mad…
Yes, sir.
-I wasn't going to tell you this--
-How can I help you?
Yes, I was just wondering
about the work dinner.
Yes, indeed.
That's right, yes, that's today.
Then I'll see you this evening.
Yes, goodbye.
Goodbye.
Cho Gyeong-seon?
Yes, Cho Gyeong-seon.
I've never seen people whispering
while drinking at a barbecue place.
Yes, it was Cho Gyeong-seon.
But how come none of us recognized her?
I didn't recognize her, either.
Then I saw her name tag.
I realized only after
reading the name tag.
But that man.
-He works at Mi-jeong's company, right?
-Yes.
-Then was he her little brother?
My gosh. That poor thing.
Oh, no. He even has a kid.
I know, right?
Cho Gyeong-seon as a sister-in-law.
Isn't it obvious why they got divorced?
Hey, keep it down.
You'll get in trouble again.
Apparently, he and his two sisters
all live together with his kid.
-The three of them?
-Yes.
-Gyeong-seon hasn't gotten married?
-Of course not.
Her sister hasn't either.
Oh, my God. That guy has it so tough.
You know what she's like.
Remember when she turned
the teachers' room upside down?
What?
-You haven't heard that story?
-No.
She went to get her official
school records to apply for jobs.
Apparently, her second-year homeroom
teacher wrote just two words on it.
"Poor behavior."
Unbelievable.
Wait, who was the teacher?
German, Class 2-8.
Oh, God, German.
She turned the place upside down,
saying he was stopping her
from getting a job and ruining her future.
Even the police came.
She wasn't exactly a model student.
The teacher kept giving her a hard time
since she'd transferred from Seoul.
In the end, he totally
screwed up her life with two words.
Eun-woo went to
Cheongryang Night School, right?
-Yes.
-She saw her on campus.
And she thought, "What's she doing here?
Didn't she hate studying?"
And it turned out
Gyeong-seon couldn't get a job
with "Poor behavior."
She needed a college diploma.
She said she went to college
thanks to that teacher.
That's crazy.
You can't really see the bruises.
I put on a ton of concealer.
Gyeong-seon's sister's bar
is just over there past that alley.
Do you want to go?
We weren't even that close.
I am curious, though.
One beer before we go home?
If Gyeong-seon hears about
what you said back, you're screwed.
She'll pull out your hair.
I doubt he'll tell her.
His kid will.
Don't go. It's better not to get
involved with her.
And the treatment wasn't that cheap.
You paid as much as you should.
How did the lottery tickets I gave
your brother the other day turn out?
What lottery tickets?
Your brother didn't let me
pay for the food,
so I gave him some lottery tickets.
I got them from someone too.
Did he win any money?
Hold on, let me ask.
Why isn't she texting me back?
Gift card number.
Where's the number?
ILHAENG GIFT CERTIFICATE
So that's where you scratch off.
There it is.
Five, three,
two, one, six.
You're so fast.
There. Click there.
Don't act like you know.
Watch and learn.
Soon, you and I won't even
know how to turn on the TV.
I'm home.
You're late. Have you eaten?
Yes. I ate.
What are you doing?
Hold on. I had something to ask you.
What was it?
I forgot. What was it?
Whatever.
Right!
Hey, Cho Tae-hun!
Hey. He says none of them were winners.
Not even one?
He didn't even win 5,000 won?
No.
"No"? Is that it?
GONDAL-RO ENTRANCE
Hey.
Did you just get back?
Don't make me talk.
I have to keep my momentum.
If I stop, I won't make it.
I think I get why old people jaywalk.
Once you stop, you can't move.
You have to keep going.
With all the strength
you have left after work,
you always drink
and take the last train home!
I respect you, Gi-jeong!
You got this! Keep going all the way home!
I got this.
I can do it.
If I die,
it will be because of
commuting to Seoul for work.
Aren't you going to wash?
I wish there was a machine to wash you.
Are you a man or a woman?
There are only two ways to make money now.
Cryptocurrency, or becoming a YouTuber.
What else is there?
Nothing. And who here has what it takes
to be a YouTuber? No one.
So cryptocurrency is the only way.
I've heard a lot of people made
a fortune investing in cryptocurrency,
but never actually seen one.
Shall I show you?
I know tons of people who have.
Either way, stocks are best.
Your L Electronics stock
must have skyrocketed these days.
-I sold that ages ago, man.
-See? Crypto is better.
Just try putting in ten million won.
I don't have that kind of money.
Is your mom
still confiscating your salary?
Even banks let you off if it's been
five years since you messed up.
Your mom…
Does your mom invest it or something?
What does she do with your salary?
She saves it, I guess.
Hey, go right now and tell her,
"Mom, housing prices
are the lowest right now."
"I must buy a house immediately."
"Even if I have to take out a loan,
I must buy a house."
"Mom, saving it is…"
Chang-hee, you…
Do you think I don't know that?
Don't order me around.
She yelled at me to take the table away,
saying her sales were dropping.
I almost thought
I was from a rival company.
We work for the same company!
She only cares about her own stuff.
She's so greedy.
Chang-hee…
sits next to Jeong A-reum.
For two years.
Hey, Yeom Chang-hee
doesn't have to pay today.
-Not for the rest of his life.
-That's right.
Being next to her must be tough.
Whenever A-reum opens her mouth,
it makes me feel so suffocated.
I can't even stand
the sight of her circle contacts now.
Her eyes are soulless.
It's suffocating to be looking at her.
My blood pressure's going up
thinking about it.
I only see her once or twice a week,
but it feels like
she's ruining my entire life.
A-reum just talks so much
that it bores people to tears.
I know.
I talk a lot too.
Well…
I find it fun to hear you talk.
You've fallen for me.
Every time I hear your voice,
my ears prick up.
"Yeom Chang-hee's talking!"
You really have fallen for me.
Why are you suddenly quiet?
I don't know.
-Say something.
-I'm embarrassed.
-Good night.
-See you!
Bye, get home safe!
-Call me!
-Yes, sure.
-Don't drink too much.
-Okay.
I'll call you! Bye.
-Where?
-Yeom Chang-hee!
You're with us, pal.
-Why are you going this way?
-Am I?
Am I?
-Something's up.
-How suspicious.
Bye.
-How fishy. Something's up with them!
-What are those eyes?
Where do you think you're going?
We were all going for a second round.
-What's this?
-What's going on?
-What's going on here?
-My gosh.
-What the…
-What?
-When did that start?
-Look at him smile.
Let's go.
DRINKING COFFEE LIKE IT'S WATER
EITHER BE SUPER HOT OR NOT AT ALL!
WHAT'S A GOOD STEADY SELLER BOOK?
#BOOK COLLECTOR #READING IS HABITUAL
DA-YEON
43 POSTS 310 FOLLOWERS 123 FOLLOWING
JOY SUPPORT CENTER
I don't mean to be fussy about it.
But you know,
I also have to report to someone.
There must be some kind of document
to show what it is you do
at the Liberation Club.
Do you have anything?
Like, "this is what we do?"
Anything?
Then how about keeping
a journal of your activities?
Do we need to have our diaries
checked at our age?
Why is this making me so mad?
I must be the problem.
My father passed away when I was young.
Weirdly, it was my dad's handwriting
that reminded me of him the most.
I didn't feel much
when I saw his clothes or photos of him,
but his handwriting
weirdly really reminded me of him.
He wasn't one to use a pen a lot,
so he just had the one address book.
I looked at it every day.
And this was written in the book.
"What does a man live for?"
I'd never thought
he would ponder things like that.
The weather's so hot.
SOJU
Why don't you just buy four bottles?
Then you won't
have to come back later. It's hot.
Did you have dinner?
I didn't feel like it.
What are you doing later?
What can I do
with your whole family around?
Goodness.
Shouldn't you just get me a new one?
You scrape it off, and then it comes back.
It's no use.
That's just what happens to freezers
that are kept outside in the summer.
This is hard work.
I could have done it myself.
Chang-hee!
-Why won't you check your messages?
-What messages?
The group chat! Are you ignoring it?
Seeing how she keeps
sending messages in the group chat,
I think she's waiting for you to reply.
Why aren't you responding?
Given the mood that night, it seemed like
you'd text her right away to ask her out.
Why didn't you?
Haven't you gotten over Ye-rim yet?
There's nothing to get over.
Then what?
Isn't Da-yeon on par with Ye-rin?
Sure.
Then why aren't you calling her?
The fact that she's on par
with Ye-rin means
that she's the kind of woman
who wants a kid.
And I think the kind of woman
I'm drawn to deserves that kind of life.
But the problem is, I'm not
a man who can offer that to her.
So that's my dilemma.
And because I keep dating girls
without resolving this dilemma,
I keep breaking up with them.
Would it be any different with Da-yeon?
What she wants is obvious,
and I know I can't give it to her.
You can just date her for now.
Do you think she just wants to date?
She's not getting any younger either.
Yes.
Of course. Yes, I know.
I see.
Yes.
Yes, goodbye.
Don't mention it. Yes. Bye.
CALL ENDED
BYEON SANG-MI
Why aren't you asleep?
I'm hungry,
but there's nothing I want to eat.
Then it's not food you want.
He wouldn't let me pay for the food.
I said I'd pay for it all,
but he insisted on leaving it out.
Store owners don't actually
mean it when they say that.
If I insist,
they let me pay for all of it in the end.
But he didn't do that.
"Yes, this guy's pretty great."
So I gave him all ten tickets.
Plus, I made a mistake the other day.
I'm sorry
for giving the tickets to someone else.
You look much softer
when you're talking about him.
No, I can't. He even has a kid.
So what?
It's not like you're going to marry him.
"Anyone this winter."
He works at the same company as my sister,
so if it goes badly,
it'll be awkward for her too.
And he's my friend's younger brother,
and she's really something.
But despite all that,
you already fell for him.
As soon as someone catches my eye,
I fall in love with them.
I don't go through the stages.
Other people take an interest
and slowly grow to care
for the other person
before they really fall in love with them.
With me, it just happens right away.
From the very beginning,
I immediately fall madly in love.
How did this happen? What did he do?
It's so embarrassing
that I can't even talk to anyone about it.
I understand.
I'm also a little like that.
The strange thing is,
I didn't feel tired for a few days after.
Because I was thinking of him,
I barely felt tired.
That's why I love.
You can't feel tired if you're in love.
But all ten tickets I gave him
were losers,
so I had no other reason to contact him.
I started feeling tired
right after I found out.
The back of my neck got stiff,
and I got all grumpy again.
I'm sorry.
How could you have such bad luck?
What do I do then?
Shall I buy you more?
For me to give them to him?
Just keep getting him lottery tickets?
What's wrong with me?
Why can I not stop thinking about him?
I must be crazy.
STORE-OWNER BYEON SANG-MI
Welcome.
What can I get you?
I'm Yeom Chang-hee's girlfriend.
Ex-girlfriend, that is.
I really want to get back with Chang-hee…
But every day he spends an hour
sitting out on the street on his own.
While we watch a movie,
he goes out to take a call,
and I end up watching it alone.
I want to smash his phone.
It's just too hard for me.
I'm so sorry. I really am.
How can I make it up to you?
What do I do?
Take him back, okay?
When I heard that you broke up
because of me, I felt absolutely terrible.
I'm sorry.
Take him back, all right?
I promise
that I will restrain myself from now on.
But that will still be
30 minutes on the phone.
I'll keep it under ten.
My ex-husband used to run this store.
But that asshole cheated on me.
He used to stand here with her
pretending to be a married couple.
I got this convenience store as part of
the alimony when we got divorced,
but the only person who knows
both of them is Mr. Yeom.
I want to bad-mouth them.
I want to bad-mouth them so badly.
Don't cry.
What do I do?
Don't cry, all right?
Please don't cry. Stop.
I saw you suffering
because of her countless times.
How did you know where it was?
Dogok-dong, Byeon Sang-mi. It's easy.
I just visited a few convenience stores.
But still, pick up her calls sometimes.
I do pick up.
I'm so good at solving
other people's problems.
Should I open a business?
Thanks. You're a lifesaver.
Buy me a drink.
Let's go.
What do you want to eat?
Chicken feet?
Does that mean I have a girlfriend again?
It's better that way, you know?
You can use it
as an excuse when necessary.
-Gosh.
-It's hot.
This is nice
A PERSON THAT I JUST LIKE
When I thought about it,
I didn't have anyone like that.
If I think about it,
the people that I thought I liked
all have things
that make me uncomfortable.
Things that disappoint me.
Things that I hate.
Things that I'm jealous of.
They all have things that make me unhappy.
I might seem to be getting along
with people without any problems.
But in truth,
there's not a single person I truly like.
I'm wondering if that's why
I'm being drained without realizing it.
If it's why I always feel alone
and also as if I've been abandoned.
Hey. Here. Your pay for the week.
Thank you.
I should be thanking you.
SANPO SINKS
Excuse me.
Could I have
your youngest daughter's number?
Mi-jeong's?
Yes.
Zero-one-zero…
-I told you it's good.
-Fine, let's go.
Really?
I GOT SOME MONEY
IS THERE ANYTHING YOU WANT TO EAT?
IT'S ME, GU
Even the people I think I like,
if I stop and think about it,
they all have things
that make me uncomfortable.
There's not a single person I truly like.
I'm wondering if that's why
I'm being drained without realizing it.
If it's why I always feel alone…
MY LIBERATION NOTES
…and also as if I've been abandoned.
YEOM MI-JEONG
Is this even possible?
It's not even easy to truly like your kid.
I've decided to try finding
someone like that.
Even if the other person
blows hot and cold,
I won't let myself sway.
I'm going to just keep liking them.
Wouldn't that be better
than dealing with people
without any purpose?
I want to try living differently.
Why don't you have anyone you like?
You have your family.
I don't love everything
about my mom and dad.
I dislike my brother and sister a lot.
I just feel sorry
for my dad.
I don't think he's ever been happy.
And I think my mom thinks
she's unhappy because of her kids.
So I say this when something bad happens.
"It's fine as long as
Mom doesn't find out."
Do you think lies will work?
"You're pretty," "You're cool."
You can say whatever you want.
But the moment you say it,
it'll become the truth.
All words are like that.
Try it. Just say anything.
Subtitle translation by: Elodie Lieberman
MY LIBERATION NOTES
I'm as happy as when I get my paycheck
whenever you message me.
She must be out of her mind.
You're making me look really bad here.
Apparently, A-reum has poached
three stores that way.
From now on, I'm going to put my life
on the line and love A-reum.
I have to listen to their gibberish.
My heart started pounding,
and I couldn't say anything.
I thought I had done something wrong.
I'm going to practice now.
What could you practice
with that alcoholic?
All the neighbors know.
I don't care
even if the whole world disproves.
I let them in too much.
Why don't you keep going?
Ripped and synced by
TTEOKBOKKIsubs