MY LIBERATION NOTES
ALL LOCATIONS, CHARACTERS,
ORGANIZATIONS, AND INCIDENTS
DEPICTED IN THIS DRAMA
ARE ENTIRELY FICTITIOUS
-I'm home.
-Hey. Did you eat?
I did.
I'm home.
You girls came home together? Did you eat?
I ate.
Fold your own clothes, okay?
I can't do any more of this. Gosh.
Goodness.
She must be out of her mind.
Good morning.
We're giving out free glasses
to the customers who buy soju.
Should I get you a set?
They're pretty nice.
It's a set of four, and they're pretty.
I'll get you one.
SANPO
KITCHEN SINKS, CLOSETS
SANPO SINKS
Get in.
I'll see you later.
It's nice to be in a car
with someone else driving for once.
I got some money. Is there anything
you want to eat? This is Gu.
Pork cutlets.
I know a place near the station.
CREATE NEW CONTACT
ADD PHOTO, LAST NAME,
FIRST NAME, OCCUPATION
GU
SOMETHING GOOD WILL HAPPEN TO YOU TODAY
Tell the store owners
to keep this special term a secret.
Got it.
They know we give rental assistance
to the stores with high sales,
but they'll get jealous
if they see it happen around them.
I know.
Have him sign it by this week if you can
before other chains make better offers.
He may not sign it,
but he won't switch over to a competitor.
Five years?
Hey. I'll be 83 in five years.
Who knows if I'll still be around then?
Come on, everybody lives
to be over 80 these days.
Not everyone.
Look. I got this pair of shoes
for 160,000 won,
but they tried to sell me
two pairs for 240,000 won.
Who are they kidding?
One pair will be enough until I die.
I buy only one pair of underwear
at a time too.
They'll all go to waste when I die,
so why stock up?
I mean, it wouldn't be surprising
even if I died today.
Five years?
Jeez.
When I die,
one of my kids will have to
come and clean this place up.
The thought of it keeps me up at night.
"Just two more years to go."
"Just one more, and I'm done."
That's how I completed my contract.
But you bring me a new one?
Should I bring you
a ten-year contract then?
Keep telling yourself, "Just one more
year," and you'll live ten more years.
And when it ends,
sign another ten-year contract.
You might as well curse at me.
Then are you going to give up the store
that makes you ten million per month?
Like you said, you don't know
when you're going to go.
I've made enough money.
More than enough.
I should pack it in
while I can do it myself.
I'm done.
See if anyone wants to take over.
Why don't you do it?
DAD
CALLING
Shoot, hang on.
Damn it.
We can manage the store directly,
so make sure the word doesn't get out.
Yes, sir.
All right, bye.
It's 300 million for the deposit
and the premium?
That's a really good deal.
They earn five million won daily.
And the monthly net profit
is eight to ten million.
Just talk to your dad about it.
He'll have to sell his land
to come up with 300 million.
Do you really think he'd do that
to run a convenience store?
I already asked him once when the store
in Yeoksam-dong became available.
He called me an ingrate
who wants to sell our family land.
How else would we make 10 million a month
with a 300-million investment?
He never listens.
He won't believe me or listen to me.
Even if it rained money
and everyone in the country
started picking them up,
I'm sure he'd just be
working at his warehouse.
I mean, I respect that.
What else can I do?
What about you?
You should take over if you can.
You think I have 300 million?
Can't you take out a loan?
You think I have the assets
to borrow 300 million with?
What about your friend, Du-hwan?
All he has is his house.
I can't ask him to sell it.
This is driving me crazy.
Ten million per month
is right in front of me.
How come everyone I love
doesn't have any money?
Don't you ever end up loving me. Got it?
Han Su-jin.
Kim Ji-hui.
Park Bo-bae.
Park Sin-yeong.
Nice.
Good going.
You printed out your plane tickets
using the company printer?
Guam?
Must be nice to go on a trip to Guam.
By the way,
why aren't you
going along with them, Mi-jeong?
-Hyeok!
-Yes, sir.
What's for lunch today?
How about the usual?
Aren't you going for lunch?
What do we do?
I'm still not going to quit.
The way people look at me
when I come in and out of this building.
That's enough for me.
I used to envy people who work here.
"I want to work at a place like that."
And I work at that place now.
That's enough for me.
No one knows what I go through in here.
Who cares what my employee number
begins with?
I'm just relieved
I don't have to wear a different lanyard.
Other companies have temps
wear different colored lanyards,
so it's humiliating to be seen wearing.
Even the nearby store owners can tell
whether you're a regular employee
or a temp.
They wouldn't have invited me
even if I was a regular employee.
Because I don't own a bikini.
SOMETHING GOOD WILL HAPPEN TO YOU TODAY
It's just outside of Seoul.
I feel better when I see this.
I'll drive.
SANPO SINKS
Hello?
Gu, it's me.
Is he not home?
Gu?
SANPO SINKS
-Good job today.
-Sure. Get some rest.
Damn it.
Shoot. Let's take some out.
Why were you keeping all these bottles?
You should've had us throw them out.
You're not collecting these, are you?
Just leave them.
It won't take long.
Why don't you take a shower?
We'll take them to the junk shop.
I said, leave them.
But it'll only take a minute.
If someone wanted to clean up your shit,
would you like that?
Shouldn't we put these back?
CHATROOMS
YEOM MI-JEONG
NEW MESSAGE
SOMETHING GOOD WILL HAPPEN TO YOU TODAY
It's just outside of Seoul.
I feel better when I see this.
MR. GU
GI-JEONG
Let's have a drink.
I feel like we have to.
Stop staring.
Hey.
I'm the one
who decided to love just anyone.
You literally picked just anyone.
Hanging out with Dumbo as a kid
made you develop terrible taste in men.
We live in a small town.
What are you going to do?
What are you so afraid of?
You've been picky with men all your life.
Where has that gotten you?
You said our mistake was that
we passed on guys
without giving them a try as practice,
and that's why
nothing ever happened to us.
And?
I'm going to practice now.
What could you practice
with that alcoholic?
Don't say he's not an alcoholic.
And don't say I drink more than him.
Gi-jeong.
You be quiet.
Hey.
Yes, a little.
Yes, go wait at my place then.
It's going to be a while.
Yes.
There's some pizza in the freezer.
Weren't you going to break up with him?
I did.
Come on, don't be so square.
Hey, don't hang out with her anymore.
You stay away from Mi-jeong from now on.
You've become like her.
When I was dating Chan-hyeok,
he said he'd quit his job
and start a business of his own.
That made me happy.
Because then I could tell people
that my boyfriend
ran his own business.
I thought it sounded cool.
But then,
when he became very successful,
it made me anxious.
We weren't even married yet.
Then hise business began dwindle
because he sold defective products.
So I tried to be nicer to him than ever.
It felt like he knew I was relieved.
I was looking for someone
who'd make me look like a better person.
A boyfriend who'd make me look better.
Even with all my picking and choosing,
I never fully supported him.
I wanted him
to be more successful than I was,
but not too much.
I've never given my everything
to someone or vice versa.
I'll never do something like that again.
If my partner finds success
and I'm afraid of losing him,
I'll gladly let him go.
Even if he hits rock bottom,
I won't be embarrassed of him.
Even if everyone points the finger at him,
I'll treat him as I always did
and just support him.
Even our own parents
never gave us that kind of support.
Why are you crying?
Hey.
Can I order chicken gizzards?
Go ahead.
One plate of chicken gizzards, please!
Listen, Dad.
I'm just telling you this
because I think I'll regret it if I don't.
This is just a suggestion
so please hear me out.
There's a good store that's become
available. The deposit is 300 million.
The owner makes a net profit
of eight to ten million per month.
He's run the store for ten years
so he's earned at least a billion won.
If you want me to bring you
the sales records to prove it, I can.
Now, you might ask
why the owner is quitting then.
He's turning 80 soon.
He has two kids. One lives in the U.S.
and the other in Yeosu.
Neither can take over.
This is not for my sake.
If you think I want to quit my job
and make easy money with the store,
that's not it.
It's finders keepers. It's up for grabs.
Many people want this kind of information,
but he asked me first
because I'm the manager in charge.
If you're interested, this is
a great investment opportunity for you.
I can make a living just fine on my own.
If you want to do it,
come up with 300 million
and do it yourself. I won't stop you.
Okay.
I'll give you the money if you want.
If I divorce your dad,
I'll probably get 300 million at least.
I didn't mean that I wanted to do it.
Everyone else makes
their money grow this way.
Why is my family always like this?
Please enjoy.
-Thank you.
-It looks delicious.
-Welcome.
-Hello.
-Oh, hey.
Where's Gyeong-seon?
She'll be late.
He found the remote
for the air conditioner.
-Wait, hold on.
-Thank you.
He should stop rummaging.
Who knows what he might find?
-What do you want? Beer?
-That's it.
We'll have this and…
-Give me my beer.
-Let me.
You should've asked me for it.
I figured you'd be tired.
I only help out on busy days.
We don't get too many days like today.
Apologize!
They have fun like this. What's with them?
Look.
I didn't know people actually said that
in everyday life.
Is it just me,
or does that make you uncomfortable too?
It makes me uncomfortable too.
Right?
I mean, I had this thing
with a researcher at work.
She said, "Apologize."
My heart started pounding,
and I couldn't say anything.
Like, "what did I do that was so wrong?"
I think it's okay to say, "I'm offended,
and what you did was wrong."
But when you say, "Apologize,"
it's like coming to a conclusion
without even arguing
that you're the victim,
and they're the offender.
Right? Exactly.
Jeez, you're right.
When I heard that, it felt like
I had been sentenced to death,
had fallen into a pit,
and had cement poured down on me.
It felt like I was someone
who deserved that
so I couldn't sleep at all that night.
The worst part is
that I apologized to her the next day.
I didn't even know what I did wrong.
You're too nice.
That woman knows how much
those words throw people off.
Is asking for an apology
a new way of arguing with people?
Maybe it's like throwing the first punch.
Apologizing used to be
such an awesome thing to do.
Right?
Yes.
It used to be an act of bravery
that took self-reflection
and was excruciatingly painful.
I don't know when it turned
into such a cowardly thing
that's forced upon you.
You never really see
those brave, touching apologies anymore.
It makes me quite sad.
By the way, I'd like to apologize.
For that day.
You did. You even gave me
ten lottery tickets.
No, I didn't do it properly.
I just glossed over it.
You said getting married was
the best thing you'd ever done.
And that if you hadn't, you would never
have had such a lovely daughter.
It's been weighing on my mind
for a long time.
I realized I was wrong.
It's such a valuable relationship to you.
I shouldn't have mocked it like that.
I'm sorry.
Don't be. It's all right.
No, I'm really sorry.
It's really okay.
I think I should apologize
to your daughter as well.
Gosh, please don't.
It'd be better not to.
Are you trying to heat up the beer?
Jeez, what is she doing,
hugging them like that?
Three draft beers, please.
Coming right up.
Okay then.
You can only date someone
who scores a hundred points
only when you can date
someone who's a zero.
You always look for someone on your level.
Maybe 64,238? Somewhere around that.
Honestly, I score 78 at the least.
That's what you think.
No, I really would.
Just forget about the grading system.
My point is, don't limit yourself.
You have the whole world
trying to limit you.
So why would you want
to do that to yourself?
You're so cute.
You're so adorable.
I'm just trying to help you.
Don't drink by yourself.
I'll be home late tonight.
I'm having a drink with my sister.
I can't help but wait
for you to text me back.
But I won't let get to me
and do the same to get even with you.
I've always tried to silently
get even with my ex-boyfriends.
I'm done with it.
I love that
I don't have to measure your affection.
All I need to do is worship you.
I love it.
AVAILABLE
Hello.
God. I ran into Mr. Gu on my way here,
and it was so awkward.
I even rehearsed
what I'd do if I ran into him.
But I never thought
he'd suddenly show up in front of me.
He totally caught me off guard.
He was getting closer, and I didn't know
if I should turn my head or not.
Then I missed the right timing
and greeted him so awkwardly.
Well, Chang-hee told me to come over
to his house yesterday,
I was so shocked.
There was a dazzling light
coming from his room.
I thought there was an alien in there.
His room was full of empty soju bottles.
It was so hot in there too,
with the sun beating down on it.
So we tried to clean it up,
but he got mad at us for it.
Well, he didn't really flip out,
but anyway…
Jeez, he got angry at us
for trying to clean his room.
It was so embarrassing.
Did he ask for your help?
Did he ask you to throw them out?
If not, why would you do that?
Then what? I couldn't ignore it.
It's arrogant how you're
trying to change him.
Wait, arrogant?
You got it all wrong.
It was an amount
he couldn't throw out by himself.
That's also the amount of alcohol
he had by himself.
And he got caught.
"Got caught?"
It's not like we didn't know about it.
All the neighbors know.
Move over.
SANPO SINKS
-You got it?
-Yes.
Wait and see.
I'm going to get rid of them later.
Hurry up. Let's get it done
while he's out.
Don't.
Boy, she must've drunk a lot last night.
Hello, sir.
Yes.
What? When?
But…
Right.
I got a call from the store owner.
Someone has already signed
a lease contract with the landlord.
I think the landlord listed it for lease
when he heard
the store owner was quitting.
Why would he do that
without even discussing it?
Find out who signed the lease
and for what kind of business.
We can't lose that spot.
Yes, sir.
All right.
SANPO SINKS
I should've kept my distance.
I let them in too much.
Sometimes I'm okay with it.
But other times…
I hate the sight of people
moving around in front of me.
I hate it more when they start talking.
I have to listen to their gibberish
and have to say gibberish back to them.
What should I say?
It's taxing to think of what to say next.
I feel the same way.
Out of the 24 hours in a day,
I only feel okay
for about a couple.
And it's not like I even feel good,
I just feel okay.
I just try to get through the rest.
It's been like that since I was little.
When I looked at the kids
running around happily,
I was upset even at that young age.
"What are they so happy about?"
"Why am I not happy like them?"
"I eat and sleep. Eat and sleep."
"Why do I have
to waste such a long amount of time?"
I'd be perfectly okay if I only
got to live 8 years instead of 80.
I don't do anything
but I'm already exhausted.
Still, I drag myself along,
like driven cattle.
"Let's keep going."
"I don't know why I have to live,
but let's have a decent life
while I'm alive."
That's how I barely manage to drag myself
every day.
A cattle drive?
A cattle drive…
You must have seen it before.
A few times as a kid.
Ice cream?
I bought it
because I was drunk.
When I'm drunk,
I'm more human than I am when I'm sober.
I like that.
I didn't put it up for lease.
The real estate agency called me first
to ask if the store owner
was closing down his store.
I didn't know what they were
talking about, so I asked him,
and he said he really was quitting.
But I didn't tell the agency.
Why would I do that
when I'm not the landlord?
It wasn't me either.
But they said someone who knew about it
came to rent this place.
Do you know what kind of business
they want to do here?
A convenience store.
Do you know which chain?
This chain. The same one.
Apparently, their daughter
works at the head office for this company.
She used to manage this store.
Gosh.
She came here a couple of days ago.
Damn it.
You could've told me at least.
I didn't know my dad would go
and sign the lease right away.
I just stopped by the store
to say hi to the owner,
and he told me he was going to quit.
All I told my dad was
I don't get why he's quitting
when the store is doing so well.
I really didn't know
he'd rent the place right away.
You didn't know?
Do you expect me to believe that?
His daughter works at the head office.
What kind of father signs the lease
without checking with her first?
He even knew
to contact the real estate agency first.
Do you want me to call my dad and ask?
Should we all meet and talk?
Forget it.
Let's think of it as a good thing.
It's better than losing the spot
to another chain, right?
You're making me look really bad here.
Like I pulled
some dirty trick or something.
Darn it.
Please choose a transaction.
Please press the button.
-Please insert your bank book or card.
-Please choose a transaction.
Please choose a transaction.
Please insert your--
Please insert…
Why isn't my dad like A-reum's dad?
I was the one
who insisted on giving that store
rental assistance.
And in the end,
I ended up making the rent
cheaper for A-reum.
It always turns out this way.
The person I hate the most
takes everything.
From now on,
I'm going to put my life on the line
and love A-reum.
I'm going to love her
more than anyone in the world
and make her go completely bust.
Just you wait.
Soon enough,
you'll see the power of my love.
Please choose a transaction.
Please insert your bank book or card.
Welcome.
Please choose a transaction.
Please insert your bank book or card.
Excuse me.
Normally, I'm ready to
pass out around ten.
But it was two in the morning,
and I was totally fine.
I mean, I felt like
I could drink all night.
I almost winked at him like this.
I like him so much.
God, I almost winked at him.
No winking.
No one in the world winks anymore.
It's gone extinct.
What era do you live in?
I know, right?
But I can't help myself.
There are no steps in-between.
I'm diving right in.
I shouldn't do this, right?
I'm skipping all the steps
and running towards the end.
-I just like him so much.
-This is so frustrating.
Wink at him, and it's all over for you.
-Well, I didn't wink at him.
-My God.
But you know…
You're here.
What do you want to drink?
Apparently, A-reum has poached
three stores that way.
Her family's like a corporation.
The daughter gathers intel
and the father calls the shots.
We work at the same company,
but she has her own business
while I don't.
I should learn from her
but I don't want to.
Even if I did, my dad wouldn't.
Let me meet her.
Jeong A-reum? I'll make her
lose her ability to talk for a month.
She's doing that knowing that
people will put up with her.
That's why she keeps doing that.
She should meet someone like me
who won't tolerate it.
My story isn't over yet.
Fine. Let's hear what you have to say.
What did you want to brag about?
So I went to take some cash out,
all angry.
It was like no one there knew
how to use an ATM.
They were all so slow.
Shouldn't you use the machine just once?
They should line up again
if they need another transaction.
But they took their time
with multiple bank books.
I thought, "This must be how it feels
to die of frustration."
I felt like I might lose it.
One bad thing had happened,
and it felt as if
it was building up to something.
One day, my friend got drunk
and made a scene after a breakup.
Then he got into a fight at a bar
and was taken to the police.
And it turned out the other guy
was feeling miserable that day too.
Like attracts like. It's science.
People who are similar
always get together and cause trouble.
I knew I had to be careful.
I might meet someone
who also wants to beat somebody to death
and get into serious trouble.
I had to be careful.
Then someone tapped on my shoulder.
I'm sorry, but…
He said his bus was arriving soon
and asked if he could go first.
I guess he was taking
an intercity bus or something.
I thought, "Here it comes."
I didn't think I could say anything nice.
Welcome.
That's it?
Good job.
Call Jeong A-reum here.
Jeez.
We should go.
He probably didn't want to miss his bus.
He left in a hurry.
So I could see his bank balance.
INSUFFICIENT FUNDS FOR
THE REQUESTED WITHDRAWAL OF 50,000 WON
He couldn't withdraw 50,000 won
because he didn't enough money.
I was glad I let him go first.
It made me feel better.
But it's not because
I think I'm better off than he is.
That'd be rude.
If you ask me if I'm the kind of jerk
who takes comfort in others' misfortune,
I am.
But I don't want to do that to that man.
He didn't even have 50,000 won.
If he missed his bus too,
it would have been the worst.
Because I gladly let him go first…
Well, maybe not gladly.
Anyway, because I let him go first,
he probably caught his bus.
You see,
it's amazing
how I always know when it's time.
Time to back off.
Even when I go crazy and out of control,
I still get a hold of myself.
Things happen that way.
I think it's fate that I live like this.
I'm like a drizzle.
I may not have a big current of my own
like the river or the ocean,
but I'm like a drizzle
that soaks people without them realizing.
That's right.
I think I'll be able to afford that.
Drizzle? That's nice.
But don't forget
about Jeong A-reum though.
You brought your resume, right?
-Yes.
-Okay.
Hello.
Oh, the girlfriend.
This promotion has already ended.
I keep forgetting to take it down.
You didn't need to bring a resume.
You're Yeom's girlfriend.
I can't vouch for her.
You have to be careful.
RESUME
NAME: JI HYEON-A
"Ji Hyeon-a." What a pretty name.
May I?
When can you start?
I can start immediately.
-Really?
-Yes.
That's perfect.
"5885"? That should be easy to remember.
Memorize it already. I memorized yours.
You didn't even memorize
your girlfriend's phone number?
I guess you two are okay
with things like that.
Welcome.
All right. Let me teach you this first.
We can't take this many.
We can only take 30 bottles
from each person per day.
This is just too many.
What are you going to do with all these?
Here. Thank you.
Hello.
Here.
I sold the bottles.
This is for your friend.
Thank you.
He really sold them all.
I wonder what the man living there
was doing at that time.
Probably having a drink.
I'm as happy as when I get my paycheck
whenever you message me.
Right.
The number for the courier
has changed, right?
What is it again?
Hang on.
-Here.
-Thank you.
Something smells nice. What is it?
What?
It's my hand cream.
This one.
It's lovely.
Right? I can get you one.
No, it's okay.
It's not expensive. I'll get you one.
Try it on.
It smells nice.
Thanks.
I cleaned my house for a change.
What do you think I’ll do
in my clean house now?
Drink.
Today…
I worked hard to drive myself,
like cattle on the range.
I locked myself in that room
and drank all winter.
When I tried to sleep,
there were bottles in the middle.
I could've just pushed them aside
but I couldn't even bother to do that.
So I curled up around them
like I was incubating an egg.
I could've just thrown them out.
But it felt as if I was walking out
of my own grave.
Completely hopeless.
Looking at the soju bottles,
I thought…
"I guess this is it for me."
"There's no turning back now."
Today, I did something
I thought would take me forever to do.
I wonder if I can sleep tonight.
I'm not going to ask you what happened.
I won't ask you where you're from.
Or why you moved here
and keep drinking the days away.
I don't care if you don't know
how to write Hangul
or you don’t know your ABCs.
I won't tell you to stop drinking either.
And I'm not going to cling to you.
I'll be done once I feel whole.
That's cool.
I just worshiped you.
Why don't you keep going?
I don't think that was enough.
How much if I jump over it?
Why would I pay you for that?
Because I'll do it.
Go ahead then.
Jeez, seriously.
Can you give me
some pointers before I jump?
Don't do it.
Why not?
You need to be able to run 100m
in under 11 seconds to make it.
You need the momentum.
How about 12 seconds flat?
As if you can actually do 12 seconds.
I can!
I'm sure I can make it.
I'll make it over easily.
Sure. You have to try to find out.
Don't you dare!
How far are you going?
Are you going home?
I told you to stop!
5 MISSED CALLS
Gu Ja-gyeong. Pick up your phone.
Where the hell are you hiding?
It's time for us to move. We have to go.
You don't have to hide anymore.
He won't make it.
Damn it!
I told you not to.
Subtitle translation by: Yoon-jung Song
MY LIBERATION NOTES
So, what does it feel like to date
someone who lives in the area?
I like doing it.
I feel peace
in my heart for the first time.
Yeom Gi-jeong? Nothing's happened so far.
There's no way someone decent
is going to ask her out all of a sudden.
What time is okay for you?
I couldn't wait for us to meet.
What about filing a lawsuit?
-Please, just leave me be.
-Are you still not over him?
Don't try to help me unless I ask you.
It feels like it's my fault
for getting myself in this situation.
Where did you change your address to?
How could you do this to me?
Ripped and synced by
TTEOKBOKKIsubs