MY LIBERATION NOTES
ALL LOCATIONS, CHARACTERS,
ORGANIZATIONS, AND INCIDENTS
DEPICTED IN THIS DRAMA
ARE ENTIRELY FICTITIOUS
You sit there under an umbrella
while everyone's working.
Don't you feel sorry for them?
They're not working right now, you know!
They're on a date.
Jeez.
God, it's hot.
The weather's so freaking hot today.
Gosh.
God, he's trying so hard.
Jeez.
Let's go.
You should've parked in the shade.
It was in the shade earlier.
You should've parked so it would be
in the shade when you came out.
How am I supposed to know that?
You don't even know
which way the sun sets?
Where will this shade move to later?
I'm sure it'll go wherever it wants to go.
When it snows,
it's amazing to have a barbecue here.
Watching the snow pile up
all around, you know?
When you grill meat on a campfire here,
you think, "Where am I?"
It feels unfamiliar
but cozy, you know?
Yes.
Sounds really nice.
You should invite us some time.
Yes. Of course, yes.
You promise?
Yes.
Bye.
We'll be off then. Goodbye.
See you at school after the break.
Sure. Take care.
Why won't you accept payment
for the farm work?
It's because I like doing it.
Still, I feel bad
making you work for free.
Let me pay you.
It's really fine. I enjoy it.
But still, it doesn't sit right with us.
We should pay you for--
He says he enjoys it.
Well, why wouldn't he?
He enjoys it,
so take a hint and stop insisting.
What?
Keep at it.
I have you at my mercy.
How dare you glare at me like that?
What does it feel like to date
someone who lives in the area?
You're just like the people in Seoul,
dating within the neighborhood.
All this time, I thought
you had to take the bus and the train
to go all the way
to Seoul to meet someone.
I never even imagined you would be
able to find someone in this countryside.
It's so nice and economical.
You can even eat together at home.
GONDAL-RO ENTRANCE
Since you're tall and skinny, I can see
if you're on a bus even from afar.
I can see you too. Since you're fat.
I'm dying of hunger.
Are you that hungry?
I feel like I'm going to die.
Right. Go have dinner if you're hungry.
Come with me. Let's eat together.
No, I'm not hungry.
What's wrong?
What happened?
Apparently, Ms. Kwak
broke up with her boyfriend.
All right.
Don't you have any coffee beans?
They're in the freezer.
I'll have an iced americano.
Me too.
You said you weren't hungry.
I was just pretending.
To look sentimental.
You're lucky I forced you to eat with me.
You know, right?
How much I hate being
messed with when I'm hungry.
When is Ms. Kwak going to get married?
She should already.
You always get hopeful
when she breaks up with someone,
and become hopeless
once she starts dating someone new.
At this rate, if she does get married,
you'll wait for her to get divorced.
I never waited for her. Ever.
You know already, right?
It's not going to work.
I know.
But…
when I heard that she broke up
with her boyfriend,
my heart started beating fast again.
I don't get how you can like someone
so much that your heart pounds.
It's not that I've never
liked anyone that much.
I've never really liked anyone that much.
Anyway, my heart only pounds
when something bad is happening.
When I'm embarrassed,
when I'm angry,
before a 100-meter sprint…
It was always for bad things.
My heart never beat fast
because I liked someone.
When I really like someone,
I think the opposite happens.
My heart beats even slower.
Like I've been freed from something.
Like I feel peace
in my heart for the first time.
I guess I'm just weird.
Mi-Jeong just gave the perfect answer.
When you're happy, you just are.
But your heart pounds
when you think
you have a chance at something.
Like some kind of expectation.
When something's yours, you just know.
Does your heart pound when you get paid?
No, because it's yours.
But when it's not yours
and you know it's not,
but you think you might get it
if things work out…
That's when your heart starts pounding.
Relationships are the same.
Some married couples say,
"I just knew they were the one
at first sight."
If you ask them, they say when they met,
it was like, "You're the one."
Their hearts didn't beat like crazy,
but they were just like, "You're the one."
You just know that it's yours.
Relationships are like that.
There's nothing to long for. It's yours.
Rich people don't yearn
for designer clothes. They just buy them.
When you desperately long for something,
your soul already knows deep down
that it's not yours.
You want it, but you know it's not yours.
That's what drives you crazy.
Damn it!
Oh, my God!
So that's why I can't have a car.
Well, tell your soul that you can have it.
You try. You try telling your soul.
That things might work out with her.
You try making your soul admit that.
Damn it.
GYEONGGI SANPO POLICE STATION
Your household register is missing.
Please bring it next time you visit.
But I submitted it last time.
They ask for it every time.
GENERAL AFFAIRS
-All right. Thank you. Have a good day.
-Thank you. You too.
YEOM JE-HO, KWAK HYE-SUK,
YEOM GI-JEONG, YEOM CHANG-HEE
Excuse me?
I think there's a mistake here.
There should be five people,
but there are only four.
Four is correct, sir.
But Yeom Mi-Jeong is missing.
Ms. Yeom Mi-Jeong…
recently moved her address.
To where?
I think you should ask your daughter.
SANPO SINKS
YEOM JE-HO, KWAK HYE-SUK,
YEOM GI-JEONG, YEOM CHANG-HEE
YEOM MI-JEONG
I'll be late today.
I have a club meeting at work.
Did I tell you what club it is?
It's called The Liberation Club.
It's for people who want to be liberated.
There are only three members.
Mi-Jeong, you're coming with us today.
All right?
I'm definitely putting some
colored varnish on your poor nails today.
I have a club meeting today.
What on earth do you talk
about with two middle-aged men?
She said it's four today.
You already got another member?
The team leader of the Joy Support Center
is sitting in today.
She's even sitting in?
She must be suspecting the same thing.
That they made up a fake club
and actually do nothing.
Just come clean
before they find out it's fake.
Just tell them you're sorry
and come with us
to do our nails. All right?
-Come on.
-Let's do our nails together.
Throw out.
Oh, my…
You're organizing things
for real this time?
You should've brought stuff home
little by little. How overwhelming.
You know how far I live.
When I carry something heavy on
my way home, I just want to throw it away.
I even want
to toss out my own body somewhere.
Throw out.
Hey, can you come over to my office?
I have too much to carry by myself.
What club?
When will you be done?
Damn it!
Then what do I do?
After breathing, what I do the most
is look at this watch.
I look at it so often, over and over.
"Time really flies.
Is it this late already?"
Just like that, I look at it all day long.
24 hours a day.
I go to work, finish work, eat, and sleep.
Every day is the same.
So why do I keep looking at my watch?
I think I feel a compulsion
to live a productive day,
but there's not much to show for it.
I'm just constantly looking at my watch
and being chased by time.
As soon as I realized
I've lived that way my whole life,
weirdly, my heart suddenly started
to pound like thump, thump, thump.
Before, it was like bam-bam-bam-bam.
I can't believe it took me about 50 years
to realize this.
I'm kind of like that too.
Doesn't everyone
experience something like that?
And since you spent
all your time wisely like that,
not wasting a single second,
you were able to become
an important member within the company.
"Do not give advice.
Do not try to comfort."
Those are the rules of our club.
Okay, sure.
I may not be able to be completely
liberated from time,
but resting when I've done enough,
and waking up when I've slept enough…
Finding my own rhythm like that
might be the liberation I need the most.
So I've decided
to name my plan "Finding My Own Rhythm."
My time is up.
We divided up the speaking time
by the number of people here.
Otherwise only talkative people like me
would speak.
That's nice.
Who's next?
May I?
Sure.
Thank you.
STOP FEELING ****
Why is this…
I was worried someone would see.
Someone's been calling you.
Should we take a break?
Shall we?
It's fine. We don't have to.
Let's take a ten-minute break.
-All right.
-Sure, that's fine with me.
I like it.
Now that I've participated,
I can see exactly
what kind of club this is.
I also liked your
"Someone who makes me happy
when I think of them."
It's very good. The Liberation Club.
Excuse me.
Go ahead.
Yes.
I've been calling you forever! You…
Come out. I'm here, just come out.
You said you would be done by nine.
It's almost nine, so just come out.
I'm so exhausted.
Just tell them you live far away.
I'm sure they'll let you go.
Hey, what kind of club
has only three people in it?
I have a lot of stuff with me.
So what do I do? Do you want me
to sleep on the street tonight?
-Excuse me.
-Yes. How…
I'm sorry.
Hi.
What are you doing here?
Well, I was meeting someone here.
I see.
Fancy running into you here.
I'm waiting for Mi-Jeong, by the way.
Since I have so much to carry,
we were going to go home together,
but she has some club thing.
But she's never had
any interest in those things.
Oh, my God! You're in the same club,
aren't you?
Well…
-Yes.
-Okay.
Why didn't she tell me that?
-So you're in the same club.
-Yes.
This is Mi-Jeong's sister.
-Okay.
Nice to meet you.
We'll be done soon.
Why don't you wait inside? It's cooler.
Come in. We're almost done.
Shall I?
Carry that for me.
-Let me.
-No, it's…
Those books are as heavy as bricks.
Please, take your time.
Well, shall we wrap it up? She's waiting.
No.
Just finish it up. Take your time.
Don't mind me, and take your time.
Where were we?
I don't think it's necessary
to do this often.
Everyone has their own life
-and we have work to do.
-Okay.
After I lost my dad in fifth grade,
I also lost my mom
when I was in sixth grade.
When I went to school
after my mom's funeral…
the kids made me fight someone.
Someone who could never beat me.
He was big but didn't know how to fight.
But the mood was weird.
It felt like I had to lose.
So…
I let him win.
"So this is what it's like
to have no parents."
It felt like I lost one of my arms
when I lost my dad.
When my mother passed away too…
it felt like both my arms were gone.
What if…
my daughter also…
feels like she's lost an arm?
You're coming home now?
I think you got even prettier today.
I never walked home
when she was younger.
I ran
because I couldn't wait for us to meet.
When I arrived,
that little girl would scream with joy.
-She would spin around in place.
-Dokdo is our land.
We were both so happy then.
As if we could soar high past the skies.
Ever since my parents passed away,
I've had this feeling of weakness
inside me.
I need to liberate myself
from this feeling
for my daughter to get over it too.
STOP FEELING WEAK
What's Cho Tae-hun's phone number?
I just want to ask him something.
He's my friend's little brother.
I'll hunt down
those bastards who put him in that fight.
There's watermelon in the fridge.
Have some after you wash up.
Hey.
I'm so afraid of having someone
who's really precious to me.
I mean, she's just my niece,
but I'm so scared
that something might happen to her.
It must be worse for you.
It's amazing how you deal with that fear.
You just do.
You just do when the time comes.
What's wrong? Have a few more drinks.
I'm done.
I'm home.
-See you later.
-See you tonight.
All right. Have a good day.
Where did you change your address to?
What do you mean?
She's not on the household register.
My friend asked me…
to change my address to her place.
What for?
My friend…
had filed for bankruptcy,
so she couldn't sign a lease.
So I did it for her.
Are you insane? Seriously.
Move it back to here.
You shouldn't do that,
no matter how close she is.
You should keep your records clean.
Don't deal with people
who ask you to sign things
or ask for you to stand surety for them.
So…
About my dad's store…
Wouldn't it be uncomfortable
for you to manage?
Why would it be? It's fine with me.
Why don't I do it?
-Why don't you give it to me?
-No. I can do it.
I mean,
won't it be uncomfortable if the store
owner is your colleague's father?
Uncomfortable? Never.
I treat all of the store owners
like my own mother and father.
Gosh.
My dad's hard to deal with.
My dad isn't a walk in the park either.
All right then.
Am I crazy? Why would I give it to her?
The daily revenue there is huge.
Who knows what she'll do with it?
She'll probably plot with her dad
and order tons of the new products
to get a promotion.
She thinks she's the only smart one.
Gosh, you've put a stop
to A-reum's plan for an easy promotion.
Of course.
That store's under my management.
Even A-reum must be the perfect girl
to some guy, right?
She's good at work and makes good money.
That guy will never be my friend.
I'll hate him. I don't even
have to meet him to know that.
Give me a list of the people
who put you in that fight.
I can't just let it slide.
I spent all last night
running simulations in my head.
I've already planned out
all the things I'll do to them,
all the curses I'll say,
and with what expression.
Just give me the list.
I'm good friends with them now.
How? Why? For what reason?
It happened when we were young.
Being young is no excuse.
Just give me the list
so I can at least curse them!
You're my sister's friend. Why don't you…
I'll find out myself at all costs.
I've…
got to run now.
Have a good lunch.
I was wondering if anything else
might be sent in the mail.
I can't let my family find out.
Mail is sent when there's a delinquency,
a change in the interest rate,
or if a notice needs to be given.
What about filing a lawsuit?
Your account has the transaction records.
You can file a lawsuit with that.
You can't keep paying it off for him
forever like this.
It's not a small amount.
HANJO BANK
My family is about to find out that
I took out a loan to lend you money.
We need to talk today. Call me.
Hey. Aren't you going home?
-No, I'm going to head out later.
-Why?
I have plans.
Plans? That's rare.
See you tomorrow.
-See you.
-Bye.
I'm not going home until you pick up.
Hello?
It's me, Se-yeong.
Why are you picking up?
I have nothing to talk about with you.
Let me talk to Chan-hyeok.
I'm really sorry, Mi-jeong,
but Chan-hyeok really doesn't have money.
He honestly doesn't.
I had him come over
because he might actually die
if he stayed in Korea.
Soon, my cards will be frozen,
and I'll become a delinquent borrower.
Why should I become a delinquent borrower?
I'm really sorry,
but I don't know what to do.
I'm also living from hand to mouth.
-Who is it?
-It's nothing.
Tell me who it is.
-Give it here.
-Just leave it.
I said, give it to me!
What are you two doing over there?
I guess you had the money to fly there?
I came to sell my organs.
I guess you haven't sold any yet?
I'll be a delinquent borrower soon.
Then I'll have to quit my job.
Your family has money, don't they?
They can pay it off for you so why would
you become a delinquent borrower?
Why should I ask my family
when it's your fault?
I'll pay you back.
But since it's urgent, pay it first.
I'll pay you back later.
What do you expect me to do?
I literally have no money right now.
Whatever you do,
you can make at least 1,500,000 won.
Hey, do you think you're the only one
asking me to pay them back?
I'm trying my best to make money, but
they're chasing me and ruining everything,
telling me to cough it up immediately.
How can I do that
unless I steal it from somewhere?
They blame me if I sleep,
they blame me if I eat.
Unless I starve to death,
they'll never believe me.
Stop trying to say I'm not
paying you back because I don't want to!
How could you do this to me?
Don't. Stop it!
Stop it!
I don't know how it got like this.
I just decided to focus on one thing only.
Jung Chan-hyeok…
I won't let him die while he's by my side.
Drink slowly.
It's me, you know. It's exactly me.
No one could feel weak
if they were with me.
I'm the pick-up girl,
the girl who's like a Jindo dog.
All he has to do is be with me.
I want to tell him it's me so badly.
You know, I really want to tell him
to go out with me right now.
Should I just say it?
What?
Why shouldn't I?
Who said you shouldn't?
Hey, I'm turning 40 soon.
I decided to love anyone this winter.
But he isn't just anyone,
not by a long shot.
He's a genuinely decent guy.
Tell him if you want to.
How can someone change so much
in just one month?
Remember what you said here a month ago?
Hey, where can you buy a gun in Korea?
A slap in his face won't cut it.
I should just put three bullets in him.
Time's a fickle friend, right?
Why is it so difficult
to tell someone you like them?
It's not like you're telling them
you hate them.
Because your soul knows
you're going to get rejected for sure.
If you hesitate to say something
but then actually say it,
you're guaranteed to regret it.
You hesitate
because you know you shouldn't say it.
But you still end up saying it
and making yourself miserable.
Humans are really nonsensical animals,
you know?
Du-hwan.
Stray puppy, egg white, one-won coin.
What's wrong with you,
you unbearably old-fashioned egg white?
Don't do it.
Just don't.
You know what Gi-Jeong said?
She wanted to get a gun to shoot someone
because they told her they liked her.
She wanted to shoot anyone
who smiled or winked at her.
She was always looking for a gun.
If someone below her standards liked her,
she would go off
as if they had insulted her.
Girls, you know?
If a guy they think is below them
says he likes them,
they get deeply insulted.
Every girl in the world is like that.
Except Hyeon-a.
Everyone used to like her
when we were in school, right?
Seriously, literally everyone, including
some weirdos, said they liked her.
She was so kind even to them.
Even when she was rejecting them.
When we were in college,
I saw her get rejected by guys
a few times.
But she didn't…
She didn't even get mad, you know?
She didn't even get embarrassed
or anything.
She always used to be grateful
to the boys who liked her at school
when she was young.
So she assumes others feel that way.
That's why Hyeon-a is the only one of us
who's always dating.
Yeom Gi-jeong?
She's going to love anyone this winter?
I don't think so. She can't.
Nothing's happened so far.
There's no way someone decent
will ask her out all of a sudden.
That means she has to ask first.
Someone decent or literally anyone.
But how will she,
knowing what she's done in her life?
Maybe the guy will end up
shooting her dead.
What I'm saying is that it's her karma.
But you went out with anyone too easily.
Mi-rim really wasn't a good idea.
I had no choice. She said she liked me.
But still. I can't believe you dated her.
Hey, that's enough.
She's someone's mom now.
I'm home.
-You're here.
-Hey.
Who asked who out first?
With Mr. Gu, I mean.
I did.
I didn't ask him to go out with me.
I told him to worship me.
What?
SLIDE TO ANSWER
Yes?
Hello?
Yes, what?
Hey, you asshole. How could you…
How could you ignore a message
from your brother saying he was dying?
If I were really dying,
I would've killed you before I died.
Where are you hiding?
Are you even in Seoul?
Sam-sik ran into
Chairman Shin at a funeral recently.
Apparently, he asked
if he was in contact with you.
You know he's not important enough
to be able to talk to the chairman.
But it seemed the old man
followed him to the restroom.
I'm hearing that Mr. Baek
has fallen out of favor with the chairman.
If we just step in here,
it'll be over for Mr. Baek.
Hey, are you listening?
How's Ssaebi doing?
Ssaebi?
Yes.
How would I know?
I haven't seen him in ages either.
Why do you ask about Ssaebi?
Did someone take your money?
How much?
NAME: YEOM MI-JEONG
Have you looked into this?
You'd probably be at the top of the list.
I just want to close the account.
It will mature in four months.
HANJO BANK
LOAN PAYMENT RECEIPT
Thank you.
Miss.
Cheer up.
DANGMI TOWN OFFICE
Did you buy something?
Why are you here at this hour?
I had something to take care of.
I asked for a half-day off.
You must have finished early today.
It's not that hot today.
Seems like summer's almost over.
I've changed my address back.
What if more mail comes?
That won't happen.
I sorted it out.
Did you pay it off for him?
He says he'll pay me back later.
I'm sure he will.
What's this asshole's name?
Don't worry. He says he will.
I just need his name and phone number.
I won't do it myself.
Someone else will do it.
Are you still not over him?
You're scaring me.
Why don't you sit down?
How far do you want me to go?
You could've just told me that I dealt
with it well without making a mess.
Why do you keep bringing me down?
I'm the kind of idiot,
you only see on the internet
that gives money away to guys.
Do you want my parents and
everyone in the world to know that?
You're scared of that, aren't you?
That bastard knows you are.
That's why he's doing this to you.
After money got involved,
he treated me like some headache,
but I put up with it.
Whenever he was annoyed,
it felt like it was all my fault.
I felt guilty asking him to pay me back.
It feels like it's my fault
for getting myself in this situation.
That's just who I am.
I can never understand those
who help women divorce
and rip off their problematic husbands.
Just leave me be.
Even if I look like an idiot,
just leave me be.
Don't try to help me unless I ask you.
People like me can't see things to an end
with people the way you want.
Even fighting with someone is hard for me.
So how can you expect me
to fight him to the end?
You don't seem to have a problem
fighting with me.
Because…
you like me.
You can do anything
in front of someone who likes you.
That's why
you should worship an idiot like me.
So I can get so confident
that I might even come to love myself
and be able to tell that bastard
everything I want to say.
I want you to make me that person.
Someone who doesn't worry
about other people knowing
and doesn't care what others think.
So worship me.
Eat.
You were trembling.
Come eat.
This is me worshiping you.
Water.
You'll be surprised if you find out
what kind of person I am.
You know?
I'm a scary person.
I won't even blink
if I was stabbed in the stomach.
But…
you scare me.
I get nervous when you're in front of me.
And that annoys me
because it makes me feel like an idiot.
But even though it annoys me…
I still wait for you.
Okay?
You should know,
Yeom Mi-jeong.
You should know who you are.
Keep going. I like it.
They're strays.
Seems like they were abandoned.
They must think it's safe there
since it's an open area.
They sleep there even when it rains.
They must have had owners once.
Don't go near them. It's better
not to get close to a barking dog.
You got this.
Why are my emotions like this?
They just do whatever they want.
Nothing's happened, but they're just…
Does it make sense?
This isn't in my control.
Something must be broken.
It's fine.
I may fall in love easily,
but I can hate people just as easily.
I fall in love in the morning
and hate them by the evening.
One day, I'll be like this again,
"That was close.
I'm so glad nothing happened."
The day I feel nothing will come.
It'll be like I never liked anyone.
Which one do you prefer?
Having no emotions just like before,
or being frustrated
since you like somebody?
Damn it.
This is driving me nuts.
Why don't you just tell him?
Nicely and politely.
I don't think I can.
Why not?
But how will she,
knowing what she's done in her life?
She wanted to get a gun to shoot someone
because they told her they liked her.
So how can she tell anyone she likes them?
Maybe the guy will end up
shooting her dead.
She treated a guy who liked her so badly
because he was below her standard.
She must be scared to be treated that way.
There are so many people like me.
I'm not the only one.
But why does it
feel like I'm the only one?
Please stay beside me
Please don't leave me
It's been a while since I had a good cry.
I'm so sorry.
I was arrogant and rude.
To those people who got cursed at
for telling me their feelings,
I'm sincerely praying for forgiveness.
I was wrong.
I'm so sorry.
If you still have a scar on your heart,
I pray that it will be healed tonight.
I sincerely wish for your happiness.
Thank you.
Thank you so much
for ever liking someone like me.
Thank you.
Thank you. I hope you can forgive me
for everything.
I'll get going.
See you later.
YEOM JE-HO, KWAK HYE-SUK
YEOM GI-JEONG, YEOM CHANG-HEE
YEOM MI-JEONG
See you tonight.
SANPO SINKS
What?
Hey, wait.
Wait. Hey, wait! Me too!
Hey!
Me too.
Scooch over.
TOWN BUS STOP
SANPO
What? When did you get here?
Her boyfriend gave us a ride.
Don't tell me…
Subtitle translation by: Elodie Lieberman
MY LIBERATION NOTES
Does he have a lot of problems?
You always do that
when something is difficult to say.
A good aesthetic sense?
It's something you're born with.
Tell your boyfriend about him.
Do you really do it?
"You are the greatest of all time.
You're incredibly magnificent."
I might do something wild.
I have somewhere to go.
-Where?
-Sanpo.
I missed you.
I guess you really are in Gyeonggi-do.
He'll ransack the area soon.
Yeom Mi-jeong's imagination comes true.
Ripped and synced by
TTEOKBOKKIsubs