MY LIBERATION NOTES
ALL LOCATIONS, CHARACTERS,
ORGANIZATIONS, AND INCIDENTS
DEPICTED IN THIS DRAMA
ARE ENTIRELY FICTITIOUS
Mi-jeong texts someone a lot these days.
There's a guy, isn't there?
Did you see what she said
on our chat by mistake yesterday?
"I'm off work now.
I just got on the train."
-I saw it.
-Yes, I saw it.
Who was that for?
Is it that guy?
The guy who ate at your house
and made you uncomfortable.
It's him, isn't it?
Yes.
-Really?
-No way.
-It was just a wild guess.
Seriously?
What happened?
What do you like about that guy?
Yes, what?
I don't know.
That's your answer to everything.
What do you like about him?
What makes him charming?
What attracted you?
It's okay. Take your time.
-Take your time.
-Yes.
He has no shell.
You know, there are people
who are very polite,
but it feels like it's just their shell.
A shell so hard
that it feels like you'll never
be able to reach the person inside.
But this guy
has no shell.
She called him "this guy."
So?
Can't you see a clear difference?
She called him "this guy"
when he's not here.
It means he's in here.
Gosh.
SANPO SINKS
For God's sake.
Damn.
I mean…
CHOI JUN-HO
Seriously.
This is not it. No.
ADD SHADOW
CHANGE COLOR COMBINATION!
Gosh.
SPACING?
For God's sake.
It'll be so nice not to hear that
during my vacation.
Tell your boyfriend about him.
I think I will.
My goodness.
I used to never understand
why people took pictures of everything,
but now I want to do it too.
This is the food I'm eating right now.
I wonder what you're eating.
Why don't we…
The sky looks beautiful today.
You're right.
Isn't that what you call a vanilla sky?
-It's clearly a vanilla color.
-The things I'm doing.
-The things I'm seeing.
-The clouds look pretty.
-Or was it sky vanilla?
-Why do I want to share them with you?
I know you wouldn't be interested.
It's pretty.
CHO TAE-HUN
CHO TAE-HUN:
I'VE GOT TO RUN NOW. HAVE A GOOD LUNCH.
SURE. YOU TOO.
I LIKE IT
POP
Shoot.
DELETE FOR EVERYONE
He wouldn't have seen it, right?
I'm sorry. I sent that by mistake.
Okay, I got it. Bye.
YEOM GI-JEONG:
DELETED MESSAGE
I'M SORRY. I SENT THAT BY MISTAKE.
I wonder what it was.
Your vacation starts tomorrow.
Do you have any plans?
What?
Well…
I might do something wild.
I wonder what it was.
I miss you. Let's meet.
Would you like a drink?
No, I don't drink when I eat.
I rarely eat and drink together.
You're truly a master of alcohol.
Can I ask you something?
Do you really do it?
Worship, I mean.
"You are the greatest of all time.
You're incredibly magnificent."
Do you do stuff like this?
Mi-jeong didn't ask him to date her.
She asked him to worship her.
And he said yes, apparently.
You did, right?
"Heil, Hitler.
You're the greatest of all time."
Isn't that what worship is?
Have pity on her.
She said she'd love
just anyone this winter,
but well…
She hasn't…
Call Mi-jeong and ask where she is!
She'll be late. She's still at work.
Gosh.
She'll have to eat alone.
ADD SHADOW
CHANGE COLOR COMBINATION!
SPACING
THICKER LINES, CHANGE FONT
CREDIT LIMIT AND PAYMENT DATE
CREDIT CARD USER GUIDE
THANK YOU FOR JOINING JOY CARD.
WE WILL BE YOUR HAPPY COMPANION.
Gosh. This isn't it.
If I imagine that I'm sitting here
working next to you,
even awful tasks like these
turn into something beautiful.
Work becomes bearable.
I'm playing a role
of a woman who is loved.
A woman who has everything she needs.
Yeom Mi-jeong's imagination comes true.
The way you drink is weird.
You just sit still
as if you're spacing out.
I drink to feel high.
I…
drink to feel calm.
When I drink,
it feels like the puzzle pieces
that have been floating around
in my head fall into place.
It also makes me gentle, I think.
What goes around inside your head?
Curses.
I curse all day inside.
Curse at who?
I don't know.
There must be a story behind it.
There's no story. I just curse.
I always curse
except when I drink,
when I sleep,
and…
when I talk like this.
Mi-jeong told him to worship her.
She's unbelievable, isn't she?
Does he have a lot of problems?
I have a feeling he does.
I think Mi-jeong did that to save him.
What?
SANPO SINKS
"You're the greatest of all time."
What are you doing?
I think that's Gu.
What?
Where?
In that truck over there.
Why would he be driving a truck?
That's Mi-jeong.
She never really looked at the camera
when she was little.
Turning the hip is still hard.
-What do you think?
-It looks great.
You think so? Look.
Yes.
It's better to straighten your arms.
-Did they finish reviewing?
-Yes.
Put it on my desk.
A good aesthetic sense?
It's something you're born with.
Sense of color?
It's not something you can learn.
I agree.
This is what they chose
after thinking about it for a month?
I wonder why they picked this
out of all the other green ones.
Do you know how it was chosen?
JOY CARD
My instinct tells me
that this is the one.
A bouquet in spring…
After all that time,
it was settled by one person's instinct?
The thing is,
I thought that was the best design
from the beginning.
But if I had told them,
would they have listened?
Those who deliver results
are always right.
We haven't delivered any results.
Still, I was grateful to her
for saying that.
I thought they were
in a different league from me,
but they just follow their instincts.
I think you're unhappy
because you don't know how good you are.
Be gentle with the door.
Good.
SUMMER VACATION
AUGUST 6 - AUGUST 11
Seriously. How much did you think
we were going to eat on an overnight trip?
We shouldn't have unpacked it.
Don't pack like this next time.
Stop yammering and move them.
I'm so sick of it.
All the packing and unpacking.
Going up and down
from the third floor. Seriously.
Jeez.
Hello?
Yes. I'll go pick it up.
Bye.
I have somewhere to go.
Where?
Where are you going?
Someone's selling Nirvana's second album.
I'll go listen to it before I buy it.
-Where is it?
-Sanpo.
That's going to be a long trip.
You've been driving for hours already.
It won't take long.
Jeez, you should just buy it.
Why go through all that trouble?
There are some people
that sell unusable albums.
Boy, you'll be driving all day.
Hey, if it's Sanpo,
you could just ask Gi-jeong.
Hang on.
I'm sorry for all the trouble.
No, it's close from here.
It won't take long.
BUS STOP
SANPO
Here we go.
You made scoring a good album so easy
for me. Thank you so much.
You're welcome.
I'm on vacation right now.
If you could ask Mi-jeong to give it
to me next week, I'd appreciate it.
Sure, I will.
Thank you so much.
I'll treat you to a nice meal.
I'll look forward to it.
I'm going to Seoul on Saturday.
Would you like me to give it to you then?
If I could have it even one day sooner,
that would be great.
What time should I meet you?
I missed you.
MANAGER CHO TAE-HUN:
I'LL GET IT FROM YOUR SISTER MYSELF
THIS SATURDAY
I SEE. OKAY.
GOING WITH THE FIRST DRAFT
Proper posture comes first.
Being accurate over being fast.
Okay. You're doing great.
One, two, three, four…
Attention. Bow.
Thank you!
Good work, guys.
Hey, no running! Come on.
Walk! You'll hurt yourselves!
TEACHERS' ROOM
KWAK HUI-SU
Come. Let's talk over dinner.
There's nothing romantic about apartments.
You can't see the house
of the woman you like from a distance.
I wish there was a day set by the country
where people confess their love.
For shy guys like me.
My dad is shy, but he managed
to get married and have three kids.
-This is good.
-There he goes with the left.
My heart is running ahead,
but there's nothing I can do.
I can't call her.
I just keep looking at her profile
picture. I pine and fret all by myself.
If you put together all the pent-up energy
from people like me,
it'd be more than enough
to run a nuclear power plant.
That's how much energy
I have bottled up inside me.
I mean, it's a big loss for the country.
Hey, think about it. Okay?
Let's say there's a day
and culture like that.
Then no one would have to waste
their energy fretting
over things like this.
How great would it be?
If it was approved by the country.
There should also be a day where you
reject someone politely and considerately.
"With the country's approval,
I confess my feelings for you."
"I love you."
The country could also tell you
how to reject someone.
"I'm sincerely grateful."
"But I already have someone I love."
If I file a petition for this,
I bet many people will support me.
Let me get this straight.
You know she'll say no
if you ask her out, but you can't give up.
You want to go for it,
but you don't want to get hurt.
You want the country's help with that?
Everyone confesses their feelings,
gets rejected, and gets hurt.
Don't drag the country into this.
Well, they make new policies for
the minority and the weak all the time.
So how come there's no system
that protects the minority
and the weak in the world of dating?
You can't expect the country
to look after your faint heart too.
I'm saying, there should
be a culture like this.
"I'm expressing my feelings for you
in the politest way possible
allowed by the social system."
In other words, a healthy dating culture.
You're telling people you like them,
not hate them. What's wrong with it?
Let's say it's approved by the country.
If you tell her,
will she reject you or not?
Let your soul answer.
Will she reject you or not?
You can't lose your job.
She's the principal's daughter.
What if it goes wrong?
If I get rejected,
I'll just say I don't remember.
I heard a story about two people
who had accidents while riding bikes.
Neither of them remembers the accident.
One of them was crossing a bridge
over the Han River on a bike,
but when he woke up,
he was in the hospital,
wearing a patient's gown.
He was like, "What's going on?"
He must've fallen at some point.
But he doesn't remember it at all.
He was riding a bike
and he just blacked out.
The other one remembers riding a bike
in the afternoon. Right?
But he woke up in the middle of the night
shivering in the cold
and found himself sprawled out in a bush.
He got a call from his friend,
and he asked,
"Where am I? Why am I lying here?"
The strange thing is,
neither of them remembers what happened.
If I ask her out and get rejected,
come and hit me with your motorcycle.
I'll bust out my acting chops
and pretend to pass out.
What will she do if I say
I don't remember? Have me fired?
You think she'd believe that?
I'll try.
I'll give it a go
and see if it works or not.
Just give me a little push
and I'll fall on my own.
Cut it out!
Is it that hard? It's just a little push.
Don't even think about it.
Who's the poor guy this time? Jeez.
-Just--
-Here we go again!
Aren't you too old for this now? My God.
Hey, you better be there.
It's Saturday at 3 p.m.,
in a coffee shop near Gangnam Station.
I'll text you the address.
Yes.
That's right. The color is spring bouquet.
Yes, I got it.
-By the way, about the brochures.
-Yes.
The first draft looks good,
but why does it always look bad
after the revision?
CHOI JUN-HO
I see.
I'll advise the employees.
All right.
GOING WITH THE FIRST DRAFT
Ms. Yeom.
Yes?
You uploaded the brochure
to the cloud storage, right?
Yes.
I'll take it from here.
You worked hard. Go home early today.
SUPERMARKET
What about the booze?
Just these.
Buy them now if you're just going
to come back later.
I was so happy to see you
I almost hugged you.
Mi-jeong is doing a great deed.
I have this crazy friend
who used to live here.
She said she wanted to come and meet you,
but I told her not to.
I don't think you'll like each other.
Why not?
You always do that
when something is difficult to say.
You hesitate.
You guys are similar.
In what way?
You're both tough.
You're both wild
and transparent.
Transparent?
You're crazy.
You are transparent.
Are you worshiping me right now?
Yes.
ALPHA RETAIL
You applied for
the product development team.
Yes.
Why?
Because you might miss the promotion?
Or are you expanding your career path?
Well, yes.
Do you know eight people
applied for it from our branch alone?
They're hiring 3, but 67 people applied.
Have you ever beaten such odds?
I beat the odds of one in 100 million
when I was conceived.
Anyway, your chance
of getting promoted is one in ten.
So it's much better
to go all-in on the promotion.
Isn't it unreasonable to give up
the odds of one in ten
and go for one in twenty?
When you're driven into a corner,
you can't even do simple math.
What are you working on?
God damn it.
INCOMING CALL
SLIDE TO ANSWER
1 MISSED CALL
Just answer it.
Sam-sik said he saw you
at a gas station in Gyeonggi.
Is it true?
He said you were driving a truck.
Baek was there too, you idiot.
SANPO
KITCHEN SINKS, CLOSETS
You called me straight away.
I guess you really are in Gyeonggi-do.
You've been pretending to be somewhere far
when you were right outside Seoul?
I didn't pretend.
Sam-sik is sure it was you.
He'll ransack the area soon.
If Baek finds you, you're screwed.
You should pay him a surprise visit
and hit him from behind.
Let's throw the first punch, man.
Well, look.
I'll do that eventually, but…
"But"?
I'm just
too busy right now.
Doing what exactly?
-I have to go.
-Wait, man. Hey--
Tomorrow at 3 p.m. I'll be at a cafe
named Troppo near Gangnam Station.
Jeez.
LEAVE CHATROOM
CONFIRM
YEOM CHANG-HEE LEFT HAS LEFT THE CHATROOM
YEOM GI-JEONG HAS INVITED YEOM CHANG-HEE
I may not even tell him how I feel.
And if I do and it's not a big deal,
I won't do anything.
Just have my back like insurance.
If I get rejected, it'll be embarrassing
to walk away awkwardly.
I need to fall, tumble, or faint
and create some accident
to be less embarrassed!
YEOM CHANG-HEE LEFT HAS LEFT THE CHATROOM
Do you know
who Gi-jeong is meeting tomorrow?
Looking for something?
The minutes of the marketing meeting.
-The minutes?
-Yes.
I have it. Hang on.
Thank you.
You're not in the same department,
and he wouldn't use it against you.
So what's the problem?
You do all kinds of stuff
with a man whose name you don't even know.
I can't even tell a guy that I like him?
Don't push me,
or I'll tell him to worship me.
Eat before you go.
Don't starve to look thin.
You'll sweat a lot again.
I listened to this every single day
back in high school.
When I listened to their music,
it took me somewhere before I knew it.
I wanted to hold on to that feeling,
so I listened to it over and over again.
Like some kind of addict.
I think I know what you mean.
I've been listening to it
over the last few days.
The first track made me feel
like something was boiling up
from deep down inside.
I used to think it was noisy,
so I didn't listen to this kind of music.
But this time,
I felt something surging up within me.
I didn't know what it was,
but I could feel it.
Right? Although you don't know what it is.
Getting to know someone
is an amazing thing.
It's not just that person.
It's like they bring
several universes with them.
For example, a universe called Nirvana.
I'm so excited.
I can't wait to go home
and listen to it.
Hey.
No, I won't be long.
Bye.
How's it looking?
I have a feeling that he's from Seoul.
I hope Gi-jeong won't need us to do this.
But she has us here
because she thinks it won't go well.
With this,
your instincts are usually right.
That's what
I've been telling you every day.
You get it now that it's about her?
Gosh, humans…
I can't do it. I shouldn't have come here.
I can't believe I'm actually here.
What the hell.
Watch for her signal.
Please choose a date and let me know.
Okay.
Get home safely.
Wait.
Yes?
It's nothing.
Wait.
I'm sorry. Never mind. Bye.
No, wait.
When there's something I want to say,
it's hard for me to hold it back.
I'll probably say this sooner or later,
so I'll just do it now.
Would you…
want to be in a relationship?
With me, I mean.
If that's too much pressure,
we could just date casually.
You're not messing with me, are you?
Is this question that unexpected for you?
I thought you knew on some level.
Well…
You didn't know?
But I've been smiling like this.
I've always been smiling.
Gosh, I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry. I…
So that's why…
Well…
You had no idea.
Sorry to fluster you like this.
I mean…
It's okay.
I thought you'd probably say no,
but I just wanted to ask.
It's fine, really.
Take care then. Bye.
That's the signal.
I thought you'd probably say no,
but I just wanted to ask.
I'm really sorry. I…
You need to pass out! Do it now!
He's coming. Hey, he's coming.
He's coming. Hurry…
Are you all right?
I'm okay.
Where…
Are you okay? Let me see.
Is it your wrist?
Are you… Let me see.
Gi-jeong!
Hey, you idiot.
It hurts.
No, don't touch me. It hurts.
I said, don't!
Where did you fall?
On the street! Where else?
It hurts.
Why are you crying?
Because it hurts!
Goodness.
My God.
Damn it.
Gosh.
Is there fried shrimp too?
-Who picked this up?
-I did.
-You're the best.
-Is this all?
Come on, Hyeon-a
came all the way here. Jeez.
I'm making a fire to cook more food.
-It's raining.
-Damn.
Shoot.
-Jeez.
-Come on, hurry.
What the hell?
-Hurry.
-You want to cover this?
Yes, cover it.
It's just a shower. It'll stop soon.
-Cover it. Hey, it's pouring.
-Come on now.
It's pouring down.
Damn.
It's out of the blue.
Gosh.
How's Gi-jeong? Is her injury bad?
Well, she didn't break her bone.
It's just a crack.
Which hand?
Her left hand.
That's a relief.
You guys should've rehearsed it.
Hey, I just gave her a little push.
How could I have known
her bag strap would get caught?
I thought,
"Chang-hee must really love her."
"He's determined to make her pass out."
Gi-jeong has always been super dramatic.
Ever since she was little.
When we got into a fight
and I hit her even just a little…
She acted like she was dying.
That's why I wasn't worried
about her acting.
She said if I give her a little push,
she'd fall on her own.
I thought she would.
Amnesia, my ass. If you're embarrassed,
just be embarrassed.
Life is a series of embarrassments anyway.
It's embarrassing
from the moment you're born.
You're born naked.
You're right.
It stopped.
-Already?
-Yes, it won't rain anymore.
Where's Mi-jeong?
She's out with her boyfriend.
I wanted to see his face.
He's handsome.
That's not what I meant.
She doesn't even know his name, right?
I know men pretty well.
Once I see him, I'll know what kind
of life he's had since childhood.
That's scary.
How many men do you have to date
to reach that level?
All men are the same breed.
You have a relationship with one
and you know all there is to know.
-We're all the same breed?
-Turns out, yes.
Hey.
He and I are the same breed?
You're all the same breed.
I know you want to believe
that you're not, but you are.
Sense of inferiority and superiority,
self-love, and self-hatred.
You all have these things,
it's just the percentage that differs.
You all have them.
Every guy I've ever dated had them.
Here comes Gi-jeong.
Gosh, I admire you.
I mean, you're so cool.
What are you doing here?
I came to see Mi-jeong's boyfriend,
but they ran off.
You're not here to see me?
That too.
I'm sorry that I'm doing better
than you expected.
Well, let's just say that you're fine.
Getting rejected by a guy
and getting a cast isn't so bad.
What happened? You said you'd
pass out and pretend not to remember.
Jeez, not anyone can act.
I was sitting on the ground,
so how could I pass out, you jerk?
It turned out
I still have my quick reflexes.
At that moment,
I thought I might get hurt,
so I planted my hand down.
My hand moved before I realized it.
Why do I have such good reflexes? Damn it.
It was a perfect landing,
so how could I pass out, you idiot?
Jeez!
I'm an idiot for going there
in the first place.
I don't think there's anything
I can't do now.
I'm still growing even at this age.
I'm conquering yet another fear this way.
It's no big deal.
I can get over this!
You can get over this!
It's all your fault, you fool.
Come on! Help me with this!
-The fire!
-The fire.
Come on.
Do I have to help?
Come!
I'm relieved that you seem better
than I thought.
For a while, I couldn't sleep
and had a lot on my mind.
That's over, and I feel relieved now.
I feel better.
I should've done this sooner.
It's a rainbow.
It's a rainbow!
WE REGRET TO INFORM YOU
THAT DESPITE YOUR POTENTIAL,
WE CAN NOT OFFER YOU A POSITION
ON THE PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT TEAM
Yeom Chang-hee, let's get promoted!
Hey, Yu-rim! Cho Yu-rim!
Why do I want to take a picture again?
Sometimes, I have this thought.
When you were three,
seven,
and 19 years old…
I wish I could go back in time
and sit quietly next to your younger self.
You're doing that now.
When I'm 90 years old,
this will be my younger self.
MY LIBERATION NOTES
Why are you coming from Gu's house?
We're dating.
Who says something like that while eating?
But you seem better than I thought.
You're amazing.
I've looked back on it.
I'll be waiting to hear from you.
I will make her change no matter what.
I'll give my all.
Why are you following me around?
Hey, stop! Pull over.
It's really you. What are you doing here?
But someone died.
I think he got wind of it.
Say what you want to say.
I'll stop if you tell me to.
Subtitle translation by: Yoon-jung Song
Ripped and synced by
TTEOKBOKKIsubs