MY LIBERATION NOTES
ALL LOCATIONS, CHARACTERS,
ORGANIZATIONS, AND INCIDENTS
DEPICTED IN THIS DRAMA
ARE ENTIRELY FICTITIOUS
STAR CLASS
MOON CLASS
SANPO SINKS
Careful.
Yes, please put them from here to here.
Sure, got it.
SOMETHING GOOD WILL HAPPEN TO YOU TODAY
SOMETHING GOOD
WILL HAPPEN TO YOU TODAY
SOMETHING GOOD WILL HAPPEN TO YOU TODAY.
IMMEDIATELY HE SPOKE TO THEM AND SAID,
TAKE COURAGE! IT IS I. DON’T BE AFRAID.
MARK 6:50
It's just outside of Seoul.
I feel better when I see this.
Here, drink this.
Doesn't my tan look bad?
As if I got it while working on a farm?
The one who works on a farm is pale.
I'm starting to peel.
You'd think coconut crabs would taste
sweet because they eat coconuts, right?
But they're not. Not at all.
SANPO KITCHEN SINKS, CLOSETS
CUSTOM-DESIGNED FURNITURES
I'm very happy, thanks to you.
I'd had it and thought
I couldn't work with him anymore.
And, again,
there was no way
I'd find someone he'd like.
He's a different level of grumpy.
He doesn't even say
what he wants properly.
He just yells
if he doesn't like something.
How do you two just know what the other
needs without saying a word?
He just looks around, and you just
know what he wants and give it to him.
I've lived with him for 40 years
and I still can't do that.
Maybe you were partners
in your past lives.
Such perfect teamwork.
I'm home.
Hey. You're back just in time.
-Sit. Eat before you wash up.
-Okay.
A new product came out. Try it.
It must be cooling down.
Even just a few days ago,
it was still so hot around this time.
I can tell the season is changing here.
But I can't tell in Seoul.
Hey, walk on this side.
There's something dead there.
What is it?
A bird?
I hope someone flips it over.
Why do animals die with their bellies up?
Like humans.
You see a dead animal every morning
in a neighborhood like this.
The head of a rat left behind by a weasel,
or a squirrel that drowned
in a water tank.
I used to see dead frogs most often
when I was little,
but we don't have paddies now.
Back when our house was
surrounded by paddies,
frogs used to cross the street
every night,
from this side to that side.
But if a car went by then…
you'd hear them burst.
In the dead of the night…
The next morning, you'd see
frog bits all over the ground
like confetti.
But I don't know why they'd always
cross the street at night.
Was the ground too hot
for them during the day?
I used to not talk unless someone made me.
"Would anyone want to hear
what I have to say?"
But now,
I just say whatever's in my head.
It just…
comes out.
And…
I have this feeling I've never had before.
Suddenly…
I feel lovable.
Who says something like that while eating?
Enjoy your lunch.
-Thanks.
-Well, then.
Is that why?
Yes.
You're so brave.
I wanted to tell him how I felt,
but I was still scared to do it.
So I had a backup plan
in case I got rejected.
And this was the result.
You seem better than I expected, though.
My face still gets red
when I think about it.
But I can get over it
by humming to myself.
You're amazing.
I haven't seen such a spirit in a while.
To be honest, I feel okay
because of his attitude, you know?
You know, you told me I'm the type
who cares about a guy's attitude.
So the reason it turned out that way--
Thanks for the food.
-Thank you.
-Don't mention it.
Coffee's on me.
I turned my phone off that day
because I was so embarrassed.
Why? In case he called you?
No. In case he didn't.
I thought it would be better not to know
whether he called me or not
than to know that he didn't.
But then…
"Right, I'm injured!"
"It's only right
that he should ask if I'm okay."
"I'm even his sister's friend."
"Of course,
he should ask if I'm all right."
So, I turned it back on.
Are you okay?
Have you seen a doctor?
CHO TAE-HUN
You must have turned your phone off.
Please send me a message. I'm worried.
Even when I was talking
to people at church today,
my heart was heavy all day long.
Did you order my jjamppong?
I did.
I've looked back on it.
I realized
I always had fun when you were around.
You were always smiling.
I felt very supported when you asked me
for the list of friends
who put me in that fight.
Yes.
It's fair to believe that I led you on.
I'm sorry.
I hope our relationship doesn't end here.
I'd like to treat you to a meal,
as I promised.
Whenever, wherever.
As soon as you can,
I'll be waiting to hear from you.
CHO TAE-HUN
He's sincere.
Yes, exactly.
Honestly, I was terrified.
I was terrified that he'd think,
"This girl's nuts."
"How dare she ask me out," and ignore me.
But he…
The way he put how he felt into words…
It's my first time feeling this grateful
after getting rejected.
I read it over and over.
-I've even memorized it.
-He said he went to church, right?
Yes, church.
To tell you the truth,
I did a lot of self-reflection.
To all the guys who asked me out
that I got so angry at…
There have been guys.
Please don't think there weren't any.
There's your world, and there's my world.
But in both worlds,
men and women are exactly the same.
Asking out, getting rejected,
crying, and laughing…
Well, anyway,
I repented my arrogance
and decided to take a leap of faith…
and I think I did well.
Even if you get rejected,
you can learn something
if it's by a gentleman.
I think
I saw how dignified a person can be.
But that doesn't mean
I'm holding out hope or anything.
I'm not, really.
It's just,
I learned something
about dealing with people,
so I think I'll be able
to love someone this winter.
I think you will.
Really.
GOURMET PORK CUTLET
DOUBLE CRISPY
From Friday onwards, A-reum's dad owns
Branch 2 in Baehyeon.
Will he be better or worse
than his daughter?
Don't bother hoping.
Have you still not given up?
If you think about it, it's simple.
It's her dad's store.
She'll visit often to make more money.
"Let's sell this and that. Don't do that."
She'll be doing everything.
Just forget it.
You just need to focus
on your own performance.
I thought I would be grateful
if only A-reum would disappear,
but I even have to
deal with her father now.
I had a dream a few nights ago.
I had leeches on the back of my hand,
and more appeared
until my whole hand was covered in them.
So I said,
"I have no blood, I'm a block of wood,"
and all of them just fell off,
totally powerless.
What a weird dream.
Don't you guys dream?
I have at least three dreams a night.
-Hey.
-What?
So this is where you guys were.
Have you been waiting long?
Not at all.
Table for two?
Can we go first?
Sure, go ahead.
All right. Thank you.
"I am
a block of wood."
-You guys wait here.
-Sure.
Seriously.
Why are the tables at that restaurant
all so small?
Once you put your phone and wallet on it,
there's no space left to put your cup.
And you have to eat
so carefully, like this.
Why do we have to eat like that?
What did you have, Chang-hee?
I asked what you ate.
Kimchi stew.
-At Mr. Park's place?
-Yes.
You should have told me if you were
going to eat kimchi stew there!
I'd have gone there, too.
It seems the queue there
wasn't too long today.
Seeing as you came back early.
What will you have tomorrow?
I don't know
what I'll want to eat tomorrow.
How about you eat the kimchi stew
there again tomorrow?
-Do you like me?
-What?
Why do you follow me around?
What?
When did I follow you around?
Are you a narcissist?
That's ridiculous.
It's ridiculous for me too.
I'm not even your boyfriend.
Why do I have to queue for you?
When did I ask you to queue for me?
I was just asking. I can't even do that?
Asking me if I could have
kimchi stew again tomorrow
sounds like you're asking me
if I could queue for you.
For office workers, a nice lunch
is the only thing we can enjoy.
Why do I have to
give that up just for you?
Are we that close?
Why don't you queue for me tomorrow, then?
I think I'll want to have
Pyongyang naengmyeon tomorrow.
Will you queue
at Yaksan Naengmyeon for me?
Why do you ask people
for something
you're not willing to do for them?
What's your problem?
I mean,
if you want to eat kimchi stew,
is asking that we go together
something to get this angry about?
I said, I don't know
what I'll want to have tomorrow.
Hey, stop! Pull over.
Damn it.
What's wrong?
It seems there was an accident.
It's really you.
What are you doing here?
Golf went strangely well for me today.
So I thought, "This must be my lucky day."
And it turns out it is!
You, Gu Ja-gyeong, hid so well
that no one knew if you were alive,
yet I bumped into you on the road.
What are you doing here? Are you putting
on a show? Acting like you're broken?
A show?
Why do I have to act like I'm broken?
Hey, what kind of guy calls someone
and asks if they're driving
when his girlfriend died?
Asking to stop the car.
Who does that?
I thought you were talking about my wife.
But it was your girl.
You must have been acting.
You wanted her dead, didn't you?
I heard you cried so hard
when your dog died.
That you went around
with your eyes all red.
But a person died. Your girl, at that.
How did you not cry at all?
How could a human be like that?
You have no idea
how frustrating she could be, do you?
Of course not. She's your little sister.
What a relief, right?
It would've been bad
if you guys got into a big accident.
Change the rope tomorrow.
What would you have done
if you weren't with Mr. Gu?
Sometimes…
he buys this one.
How old is he?
Where's he from?
She wouldn't stop asking,
so I just made things up.
"He's 38."
"He's from Seoul."
In case she asked your name,
"Gu Ja-cheol, Gu Ja-seung, Gu Ja-gyeong."
I tried to come up
with names that start with "Ja,"
but she didn't ask in the end.
Did I get "Ja" right?
It must be either "Bon" or "Ja," right?
Are you tired?
I walked 10km.
Why?
I didn't have my wallet on me.
Rest up, then.
I'm home.
Okay. Have you had dinner?
I ate.
Why are you coming from Gu's house?
Did he ask you to buy some liquor for him?
We just talked.
About what?
Why can't you tell me?
We're dating.
Oh, my God.
ALCOHOL STATION
GWANGHWAMUN 1ST ST.
There are so many things
about her that bother me.
Why did I have to blow up over food?
That's so lame.
Why is 80% of what you say
when we drink about Jeong A-reum?
It's not like you love her.
I want to stop talking about her, too.
But I have to stop seeing her to do that.
Don't worry.
You won't once you become a manager.
It's only a few days away.
You never know if I will.
At least one of you should get promoted.
Either you or A-reum.
On the day I don't have
to see her anymore,
don't stop me.
Don't stop me. I'll give my all.
I'll go at her so hard
that she'll have to change.
I'll join your battle.
I will build you a monument
in front of Dangmi Station.
Well, you can lash out at her
if you want to.
But, hey, Chang-hee.
You…
You need to think about why you hate
Jeong A-reum so much, at least once.
What, do I have to think to know that?
Don't you hate A-reum?
You don't just hate her.
You hate her so much.
She makes me hate her so much.
For us, it's just…
"God, she's crazy. What a bitch."
Nothing more, nothing less.
Try being seated next to that crazy lady
and listen to her yammer on all day.
A woman who has no humanity at all
but is just full of greed,
talking all day about stuff
that's not even interesting. You try it!
If Jeong A-reum wasn't rich…
would you have hated her that much?
If she was a normal woman
from a normal family,
would you still have hated her that much?
Just be honest.
Am I being insincere?
Hey, tell me. Am I the bad guy?
Am I the bad guy here?
Rich or not, she deserves to be hated!
I mean, what I'm saying is…
That's enough.
What I'm saying is,
you might be just as greedy as A-reum
but just pretending that you aren't.
You know? In this world,
there are greedy people everywhere.
Why do you hate Jeong A-reum so much?
Should I hate someone I don't know, then?
She's the one I know.
I mean, what I'm saying is,
don't deny your greed,
and just take what you want.
If you become rich?
You won't hate Jeong A-reum anymore.
If I get rich?
Why would I hate anyone?
When I have enough, why would I?
Why are you saying something so obvious?
If I get rich…
Well, I'll probably
hate her just a little.
I mean…
Did I say something wrong?
I need to tell him the truth, don't I?
We're friends.
Let's go!
I'm not even some hero
trying to save his country.
Why do I feel so ashamed?
SANPO KITCHEN SINKS, CLOSETS
Aren't you going to change the rope?
Oh, dear.
I might be living like this,
but there are plenty of people
in the sink business
who drive expensive cars and play golf.
I just made a mistake
standing surety for someone.
But thanks to this business,
I managed to pay off that debt
and hold onto my land and house.
If you do this work steadily,
you'll have a good life.
I'll go buy a new rope.
Everything…
looks bizarre when it's on the ground.
It's just a nail,
but why does it look
like a woman's dead body?
That's creepy.
Whose is it?
I don't know.
I went to the mall for a change,
but it only ruined my mood.
Are they that great?
Why are they laughing so loud?
I felt so small all by myself.
Go with me next time.
I just went to buy
a stick of lipstick, damn it.
Why do I
hate other women my age who shop
in groups at the mall so much?
Because they're there to spend money.
They must have husbands. And kids too.
In front of those women,
I want to make them feel small by buying
something too expensive for them.
I want to have a body that the sexiest,
coolest clothes would look good on.
I hate seeing a family of four even more
than those women who shop in groups.
Those perfect fortresses.
We also came from families, you know?
Hey, we never go anywhere as a family.
Why would we? Seeing each other at home
is already more than enough.
The family we'll have one day…
Will it be the same
as the family we came from?
It's all the same.
But you still want to do it.
Humans are so dumb.
-Hello.
There you go. Time to go home.
-Bye.
-Yu-rim!
-Let's go.
-Did you study hard?
-Yes.
-Goodbye.
-All right, goodbye.
-Should I carry your bag?
-It's okay.
Let's go home.
Auntie made deep-fried squid.
Your auntie
borrowed all the books you need
from the library.
Studying is hard, right?
Why do you always say "auntie did this,"
"auntie did that" when you talk to me?
Just in case
people think I'm your mom,
and that makes you upset.
Your mom's so much prettier than me,
you know?
Is it good?
I envy you. You have aunties,
who cook delicious meals for you.
My auntie was…
Go and sleep if you're drunk.
Aunties are all you've got.
Your aunties have decided
to give up on being women.
But your dad…
he's still a man.
I know everything, you punk.
Did that girl ask you for a Chanel?
You've never bought us lipstick.
I already saw that thing in your trunk.
Do you think something in a Chanel bag
has to be from Chanel?
It's a toolbox.
Cho Gyeong-seon,
go to your room and sleep,
He's definitely seeing someone.
Lately, he's been looking
at his phone all day.
He changes the pattern lock now.
Hey, you never used the pattern lock
before, right?
See? I'm right.
That punk's seeing someone.
Hey! Show me your phone, you bastard!
Gosh!
I told you not to swear at him.
He's a father.
What about me?
I'm an auntie.
And I'll be forty very soon!
YEOM GI-JEONG
THANK YOU. YOU'RE VERY CONSIDERATE.
ARE YOU OKAY?
DELETE
I'M FINE. THERE'S NO NEED
TO WORRY ABOUT ME.
I'M TOUCHED.
LET'S DRINK AGAIN SOMETIME.
DELETE FOR ME
THE MESSAGE WILL ONLY BE DELETED
FROM YOUR CHATROOM AND WILL STILL BE
VISIBLE TO YOUR FRIEND(S)
DELETE
I've seen a fake nail
on the window sill of a bus once,
and it felt so weird.
It's bizarre when you see a thing
somewhere it doesn't belong.
A bird lying on the ground,
a man hanging in a tree…
even a dog on a farm.
How come you didn't drink today?
3 MISSED CALLS
WHY AREN'T YOU ANSWERING AGAIN?
I HEARD YOU MET BAEK. WHAT HAPPENED?
Why won't you answer it?
I don't have to.
Are you tired today, too?
What is it?
You told them we were dating.
Yes.
Why did you do that?
You don't even know when I'll leave.
This could've passed
without anyone knowing.
It's not a big deal
for people to date and break up.
Why keep it a secret?
I'll leave after eating some.
So say what you want to say
if you have anything.
A long time ago…
I this saw on TV.
There's this famous cliff in the US
where people commit suicide.
And they interviewed people
who survived after jumping off that cliff.
They all said…
when you reach two-thirds of the way
down the cliff,
whatever made you want to kill yourself,
didn't feel like anything anymore.
Just a few seconds ago,
they thought dying was
the only way out and jumped.
But in just a few seconds,
that feeling
started to feel like nothing.
I thought it would be the same for her.
So I told her.
"To a person who feels like
living is so painful,
getting therapy
is reaching two-thirds
of your way down a cliff
without ending up killing yourself."
And…
that she should see a therapist.
I told her that.
But…
she just jumped and died.
Who did?
The woman…
The woman I used to live with.
You told her that
because you wanted her dead, didn't you?
She was already vulnerable.
And you encouraged her, didn't you?
Yes. I was telling her to die.
It was so…
frustrating to see her suffer so much.
I'll stop if you tell me to.
The worshiping…
You can take it back.
When did you ever worship me?
You bastard. It's you that killed her,
but I can't sue you for it.
Saying you told someone
to die won't fly in court.
What do I do then?
I've got to kill you myself.
Come on. I didn't hide that hard.
Okay?
I waited with my door open,
but you never came.
You were so quiet
after taking all of my business.
You don't care about that at all.
Did you two have sweet dreams?
They should just announce it
at nine in the morning.
But at 5 p.m.?
Are they teasing us on purpose?
But if they did it in the morning,
it'd affect your work.
Are you saying I won't get it?
Whether you get it or not,
it will affect you.
Whatever the result is,
let's have a drink together tonight.
Yes, sir.
Do you have time this evening?
How about dinner together?
You said you were going to bed,
but you spent the night with that bastard?
I went to bed. Then I got a call
from him and went out to see him.
I already told you!
I'm asking why you had to go see
your ex-boyfriend for God's sake!
He said he was really sick.
How could I have not?
Why would you go just because
an ex tells you he's sick?
Yes, I would. Even if they're my ex.
Even if we broke up,
I'd go see you if you were sick.
Even if it was an ex I broke up
with ten years ago, I would go!
So?
You just nursed him all night?
You did nothing else all night? Fuck!
What else would I have done
with someone so sick?
Why are you breaking my stuff?
Go break your stuff, you bastard!
Damn you. I'll do it, too. Damn it.
You crazy bastard.
I was definitely fine.
Why do I feel different than yesterday?
You've had a drink.
I keep thinking about what he said.
That it felt like he lost
both of his arms when he lost his parents.
I feel bad since I feel like
I've abandoned a guy who wants to escape
from feeling weak.
I mean, I'm the one who got rejected.
But why does it feel like I abandoned him?
It's driving me crazy.
Hey, what is this?
I'm the one who got abandoned.
I'm the one who got rejected!
His place is just 500m from here.
Let's go.
Where?
-Home.
-Okay.
Slow down.
You don't need to use the bathroom?
"Let's run away."
Telling myself that,
I got on the train in a hurry.
Why do I feel sorry for you
when I should feel sorry for myself?
Tae-hun, be bold.
Be bold so I won't have to worry
about you.
Yeom Gi-jeong.
You're the one who got rejected.
Why are you feeling bad for him right now?
MY LIBERATION NOTES
YEOM MI-JEONG
Was it a power cut?
I love this feeling.
Feeling spent
after I've emptied my bowels.
Feeling relieved that I made it
without soiling my underwear.
I downed two iced lattes
because I wanted
to have diarrhea so badly.
It didn't seem to work all day.
But I suddenly started to feel it
on my way back home.
I thought "I can hold it.
I can hold it until I get home."
And when I was almost there,
I saw my dad going into the bathroom,
I was like, "I can make it.
I can make it to Gu's place."
And lucky me. You even have a bidet!
My butt felt so good,
I felt like I was going to fly.
I use that old toilet you crouch over.
We have three people going to work
in the morning, but only one toilet.
My dream is to be like you.
Living alone, with a bidet.
Why do you look angry?
Right.
You must have been startled.
I'm sorry.
Neither of us
got promoted.
Not me or the woman I really hate.
And since we didn't get promoted,
we have to see each other
for another year.
They say like attracts like.
Why can't I get away from where I am?
I felt like I was stuck somewhere,
but after giving it my all,
I feel much better.
Though I failed to get promoted,
I survived another day
without soiling my underwear.
Bit…
talking to you in a low volume like this,
makes me feel as if we're very close.
They say like attracts like.
What do you think
we're meant to do together?
I said, get off!
The last train has left!
SAM-SIK:
I'M AT OIDO STATION, EXIT 1
WHERE ARE YOU?
VILLAGE BUS STOP
SANPO
Hello?
He's not getting up!
Yes, can you come to the station?
AVAILABLE
Get up!
OIDO STATION
TAXI
AVAILABLE
I think he got wind of it.
He's not here, sir.
What?
God damn it.
What are you waiting for? Keep looking!
-Yes, sir!
-Yes.
Who tipped you off?
I mean, you got off
the train midway that day.
Who told you?
I didn't!
I know you ate it.
I heard rustling last night.
You always play dumb.
Go buy another one.
Subtitle translation by: Elodie Lieberman
MY LIBERATION NOTES
There are a lot of crazy jerks
who do bad things and blame you for it.
I don't owe you anything, do I?
It's just what you say when you want
to end it with a woman, isn't it?
I could picture his past at once.
A man who fell from the very top…
Chang-hee seems okay these days.
-Is he dating someone?
-It can't be a girl.
-I've just been invited over.
-He did?
-Bottoms up?
-Do you have feelings for Gi-jeong?
Hey! Get lost!
-Go!
-You keep making things worse.
If you have something to say, say it.
I still think you're okay.
Let's keep going.
Ripped and synced by
TTEOKBOKKIsubs